\*BUDGTITL FINANCE
\*BUDGALED LEDGER
\*BUDGASTA STATISTICS
\*BUDGABIG BUDGET

\*BUDGTBBC Treasury Balance At Beginning Of Cycle: %value% AU
\*BUDGINCO Income

\\Budget & Finance Ledger Income Types
\!BFINC
\-Imperial Tax Revenue:
\-Inter-Civilization Trade:
\-Orion Senate Trade:
\-Tribute and War Reparations Received:
\-Forced Labor Sales:
\-Scrapped Items:
\-Gifts from Planets:

\*BUDGINCT Total Income:

\*BUDGEXPE EXPENSES

\\Budget & Finance Ledger Expense Types
\!BFEXP
\-Military Maintenance:
\-Military Grants:
\-Spy Maintenance:
\-Additional Research:
\-Grants to Planets:
\-Unrest:
\-Trade Expenses and Tribute Paid:
\-Miscellaneous Expenses:
\-Interest Paid on Imperial Treasury Debt:


\*BUDGEXPT Total Expenses:

\*BUDGNBIT Net Balance Of Imperial Treasury
\*BUDGTDIF Net Surplus/Deficit This Cycle: %value% AU
\*BUDGTBEC Treasury Balance At End Of Cycle: %value% AU

\*BUDGLABA Available Balance For This Cycle: %value% AU

\*BUDGXXAU %value% AU

\*BUDGBIEA IMPERIAL ECONOMIC ADJUSTMENTS

\\Budget & Finance Big Item Sliders
\!BFSLI
\-Additional Research Spending
\-Military Budget
\-Uunrest
\-Grants to Planets

\*BUDGSLTO Total Spent: %value% AU

\*BUDGBFIP FINANCIAL POLICIES
\*BUDGBPOO Policy Options:
\*BUDGBSOI SELECTED OPTION INFORMATION

\\Budget & Finance Big Item Policies
\!BFPOL
\-Military-Political Economy
\-General Budgetary Policy
\-Tax Levels

\\Budget & Finance Option Text & Descriptions.
\\Ordering correlates to that of Budget & Finance Big Item Policies, above

\*BUDGGBP1 Spending
\*BUDGGBP2 Balanced
\*BUDGGBP3 Savings

\*BUDGMPE1 Peace And Prosperity
\*BUDGMPE2 Peace Through Strength
\*BUDGMPE3 Limited War
\*BUDGMPE4 Total War
\*BUDGMPE5 Holy War

\*BUDGTAXP Planet
\*BUDGTAXS System
\*BUDGTAXE Empire

\\Budget & Finance General Budgetary Policy Descriptions
\!BFGBP
\-An empire with a spending policy will use money like there's no tomorrow based on its needs. This policy can be useful for short periods of time if the treasury has collected a good surplus.
\-An empire with a balanced budget will only try to spend the money it makes that turn. 
\-With a savings policy, the empire will try to save money to build up a surplus.

\\Budget & Finance Military-Political Economy Descriptions
\!BFMPE
\-This setting allows the AI to spend up to 10% of your empire's income on military uses, and military reserves will be kept small. Only the best 10% of planets in your civilization will build military units, and only 2% of planetary income will be spent on defenses.
\-This setting allows the AI to spend up to 20% of your empire's income on military uses, and military reserves will be moderate. Only the best 20% of planets in your civilization will build military units, and only 5% of planetary income will be spent on defenses.
\-This setting allows the AI to spend 15-30% of your empire's income on military uses, and military reserves will be kept large. 40% of the planets in your civilization will build military units, and 10% of planetary income will be spent on defenses.
\-This setting allows the AI to spend 25-50% of your empire's income on military uses, and military reserves will be ideally massive. 60% of the planets in your civilization will build military units, and 17% of planetary income will be spent on defenses.
\-This setting allows the AI to spend 33-66% of your empire's income on military uses, and military reserves will be kept nearly unlimited. 80% of the planets in your civilization will build military units, and 25% of planetary income will be spent on defenses.

\*BUDGTAXD Empire taxes are deposited into the imperial treasury. System taxes are deposited into the treasury of the system seat of the planet being taxed./pEach empire's citizenry has a certain amount that they're willing to be taxed without causing unrest. Naturally, higher taxes will increase planetary unrest factors, while lower taxes will alleviate them. The ideal is to balance the amount the planets are taxed with the amount of unrest caused, to maximize an empire's income while minimizing the potential for revolt.

