\*Event001 Event: Some drifting debris has been discovered, which has allowed us to complete the %Value1% project early.
\*Event002 Event: A wandering merchant has sold us plans for the %Value1% project. It's been completed early due to the information we learned.
\*Event003 Event: Debris from a warship from before the new orion era was uncovered. The debris provided surprising insight into the %Value1% project.

\*Event004 Event: Many of our scientists have gotten together to share ideas and compare research. The result has been an increase in research points empire wide./p/p
Research efficiency is increased by 4% for up to 5 turns
\*Event005 Event: Recent discoveries have resulted in an increase in our empire wide research efforts./p/p
Research efficiency is increased by 4% for up to 5 turns
\*Event006 Event: A special symposium of scientists was convened to discuss radical scientific theories. The new ideas generated by the conference have given research a boost./p/p
Research efficiency is increased by 4% for up to 5 turns

\*Event007 Event: A child genius appeared out of nowhere and offered stunning insights into the %Value1% project.
\*Event008 Event: Stunning innovations have resulted in major progress in the %Value1% project.
\*Event009 Event: The debris of an ancient warship offered surprising insights into the %Value1% project. The origin of the vessel is unknown.

\*Event010 Event: During a symposium of scientists, an argument over research methods broke out. The arguments resulted in new ideas coming to light and an increase in our research./p/p
Research efficiency is increased by 25% for up to 5 turns
\*Event011 Event: An accident at a pharmaceutical plant caused experimental drugs to be given to our scientists. The result has been extraordinary breakthroughs in our research./p/p
Research efficiency is increased by 50% for up to 12 turns

\*Event012 Event: A group of aliens has emerged from nowhere. They have been performing publicly in exchange for aid in returning home. Our unrest has decreased on %Value1%. /p/p
Unrest is reduced by 5% for up to 12 turns
\*Event013 Event: A washed-out, almost-forgotten entertainer emerged from obscurity with a smash hit. Her performances have lowered unrest on %Value1%./p/p
Unrest is reduced by 5% for up to 12 turns
\*Event014 Event: Many of our local performers have gained fame and are doing charity concerts. Their performances are lowering unrest on %Value1%./p/p
Unrest is reduced by 5% for up to 12 turns

\*Event015 Event: Alien performers have been performing all over the empire. Their performances have decreased our citizens' unrest./p/p
Unrest is reduced by 10% for up to 12 turns
\*Event016 Event: A legendary entertainer has been performing for our empire, lowering unrest./p/p
Unrest is reduced by 10% for up to 12 turns
\*Event017 Event: A new artist, specializing in creating antimatter explosions in the sky, has appeared. Her performances have reduced unrest among our citizens./p/p
Unrest is reduced by 10% for up to 12 turns

\*Event018 Event: A small program to lessen the Heavy Foot of Government has resulted in success!/p/p
The Heavy Foot of Government is decreased by 5% for up to 12 turns
\*Event019 Event: Good News! The "No Red Tape" program to reduce our Heavy Foot of Government has met with success./p/p
The Heavy Foot of Government is decreased by 5% for up to 12 turns
\*Event020 Event: By streamlining our paperwork, we've managed to reduce the Heavy Foot of Government./p/p
The Heavy Foot of Government is decreased by 5% for up to 12 turns

\*Event021 Event: The moderate "Shorter Lines, Faster Response" program to reduce HFoG met with success./p/p
The Heavy Foot of Government is decreased by 15% for up to 12 turns
\*Event022 Event: A moderate program to lessen the Heavy Foot of Government has resulted in success./p/p
The Heavy Foot of Government is decreased by 15% for up to 12 turns
\*Event023 Event: Good News! Our recent efforts to streamline our paperwork have resulted in reducing the Heavy Foot of Government!/p/p
The Heavy Foot of Government is decreased by 15% for up to 12 turns

\*Event024 Event: Great News! The recent "Electronic Access For Everyone" campaign to reduce the Heavy Foot of Government was successful./p/p
The Heavy Foot of Government is decreased by 35% for up to 5 turns
\*Event025 Event: A major program started recently to lessen the Heavy Foot of Government has been successful./p/p
The Heavy Foot of Government is decreased by 35% for up to 5 turns
\*Event026 Event: Sir! Our recent attempts to reduce the amount of paperwork we use have also resulted in reducing the Heavy Foot of Government./p/p
The Heavy Foot of Government is decreased by 35% for up to 5 turns

\*Event027 Event: A massive program to lessen our Heavy Foot of Government has resulted in success./p/p
The Heavy Foot of Government is decreased by 50% for up to 5 turns
\*Event028 Event: The massive "Automated Administration" campaign to reduce the Heavy Foot of Government was a brilliant success./p/p
The Heavy Foot of Government is decreased by 50% for up to 5 turns
\*Event029 Event: Our reduction in paperwork has also resulted in reducing the Heavy Foot of Government./p/p
The Heavy Foot of Government is decreased by 50% for up to 5 turns

\*Event030 Event: Miners demanding higher pay have gone on strike. Mining production on %Value1% has been reduced./p/p
Mining efficiency is reduced by 5% for up to 5 turns
\*Event031 Event: A coalition of miners on %Value1% have gone on strike, reducing our mining production./p/p
Mining efficiency is reduced by 5% for up to 5 turns
\*Event032 Event: The miners on %Value1% have refused to work until their employers approve pay raises. Mining production has been reduced on that planet./p/p
Mining efficiency is reduced by 5% for up to 5 turns

\*Event033 Event: Pests from a visiting freighter escaped the biocontainment perimeter and began breeding out of control. Agricultural output on %Value1% has been reduced./p/p
Bioharvest efficiency is reduced by 5% for up to 5 turns
\*Event034 Event: An infestation of pests has occurred on %Value1% and has reduced the agriculture output of the planet./p/p
Bioharvest efficiency is reduced by 5% for up to 5 turns
\*Event035 Event: Several creatures have escaped on %Value1%, and they're eating the crops and will reduce the agricultural output of the planet until they've been contained./p/p
Bioharvest efficiency is reduced by 5% for up to 5 turns

\*Event036 Event: Citing extreme safety hazards, miners refused to return to work on %Value1%. As a result, mining production has fallen drastically./p/p
Mining efficiency is reduced by 25% for up to 12 turns
\*Event037 Event: Mining production has fallen drastically on %Value1% due to safety hazards./p/p
Mining efficiency is reduced by 25% for up to 12 turns
\*Event038 Event: Safety hazards have arisen on %Value1%. Mining production there has been reduced until the cleanup is complete./p/p
Mining efficiency is reduced by 25% for up to 12 turns

\*Event039 Event: An infestation of pests has occurred on %Value1% and has reduced the agriculture output of the planet drastically./p/p
Bioharvest efficiency is reduced by 5% for up to 5 turns
\*Event040 Event: Large locust type creatures have descended on %Value1% and are eating the crops. The agricultural output of the planet has been greatly reduced./p/p
Bioharvest efficiency is reduced by 5% for up to 5 turns
\*Event041 Event: The harvest on %Value1% has been greatly reduced due to an infestation of pests not native to the environment. Cleanup is underway./p/p
Bioharvest efficiency is reduced by 5% for up to 5 turns

\*Event042 Event: Miners throughout %Value1% left their jobs and began picketing their employers' headquarters. Mining production has decreased./p/p
Mining efficiency is reduced by 40% for up to 12 turns
\*Event043 Event: Mining production on %Value1% has been reduced due to worker strikes. Negotiations are underway./p/p
Mining efficiency is reduced by 40% for up to 12 turns
\*Event044 Event: The production on %Value1% has been greatly disrupted due to a worker revolt./p/p
Mining efficiency is reduced by 40% for up to 12 turns

\*Event045 Event: A plague of alien vermin devastated an entire continent's croplands on %Value1%. The problem has been contained, but agricultural output has been drastically reduced./p/p
Bioharvest efficiency is reduced by 35% for up to 12 turns
\*Event046 Event: An infestation of pests has wiped out an entire continent's agricultural output on %Value1% for the turn./p/p
Bioharvest efficiency is reduced by 35% for up to 12 turns
\*Event047 Event: The largest continent on %Value1% had its agricultural output grind to a halt due to an infestation of insects./p/p
Bioharvest efficiency is reduced by 35% for up to 12 turns

\*Event048 Event: Miners on %Value1% quit their jobs today in a labor dispute. Mining production fell drastically on the planet./p/p
Mining efficiency is reduced by 65% for up to 12 turns
\*Event049 Event: Due to a worker revolt, the production on %Value1% has been drastically reduced./p/p
Mining efficiency is reduced by 65% for up to 12 turns
\*Event050 Event: A failed labor dispute has brought worker production on %Value1% to a grinding halt. Negotiators are working on the problem./p/p
Mining efficiency is reduced by 65% for up to 12 turns

\*Event051 Event: Alien vermin escaped from a visiting freighter and have devastated the agricultural output of %Value1%. If food is not shipped in, starvation is almost guaranteed./p/p
Bioharvest efficiency is reduced by 75% for up to 12 turns
\*Event052 Event: A plague of insects has almost completely destroyed the agricultural output of %Value1%./p/p
Bioharvest efficiency is reduced by 75% for up to 12 turns
\*Event053 Event: The agricultural output on %Value1% has been destroyed due to ravenous insects that have descended onto the planet./p/p
Bioharvest efficiency is reduced by 75% for up to 12 turns

\*Event054 Event: Disruption of neural networks caused by playful AI led to corrupted research data, which caused a minor, empire-wide slowdown in research./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 5% for up to 12 turns
\*Event055 Event: The artificial intelligence units being used to compile our research have failed and caused an empire-wide slowdown in research./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 5% for up to 12 turns
\*Event056 Event: The processing units being used for our research have proven faulty. The correlation of data has been reduced, causing a slowdown in our research./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 5% for up to 12 turns

\*Event057 Event: Several assumptions by our research staff have proven to be false. Research empire-wide has slowed down accordingly./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 5% for up to 5 turns
\*Event058 Event: Our research has slowed down empire-wide due to mistakes made by our research staff./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 5% for up to 5 turns
\*Event059 Event: One of our newer scientists has come up with some bizarre conclusions. Research has slowed down while we disprove his theories./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 5% for up to 5 turns

\*Event060 Event: An undetected machine fault created a malicious AI. The rogue caused a significant slowdown in research before it was isolated and eliminated./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 10% for up to 12 turns
\*Event061 Event: A faulty AI unit has corrupted a large amount of research data. Our research has been slowed while the problem is resolved./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 10% for up to 12 turns
\*Event062 Event: A mechanical glitch has resulted in lost research data. Our research production has been slowed while scientists sort through the mess./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 10% for up to 12 turns

\*Event063 Event: The lead researcher for the %Value1% project has gone rogue and refused to contribute to the project any longer. As a result, the project suffered a setback.
\*Event064 Event: The %Value1% project has suffered a major setback due to the lead researcher who has quit the project.
\*Event065 Event: The lead researcher for the %Value1% project has quit, causing a setback in the project.

\*Event066 Event: Our research staff has become preoccupied by several important new theories. Empire research levels have slowed down accordingly./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 10% for up to 5 turns
\*Event067 Event: Several new theories made by research staff have turned out to be false. Research production has dropped while scientists disprove the claims./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 10% for up to 5 turns
\*Event068 Event: The scientific theories that some of our research was based on have been disproven. Research has slowed while our scientists update their calculations./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 10% for up to 5 turns

\*Event069 Event: Destructive AI have gone on a rampage and destroyed months of work in our research facilities. Empire-wide research has been drastically affected./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 25% for up to 12 turns
\*Event070 Event: Some of our AI's collecting research data have proven to be faulty. The loss of data has had a devastating effect on our research progress./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 25% for up to 12 turns
\*Event071 Event: A faulty AI in our research storage facility has caused a major setback in our research. An empire-wide slowdown has occurred while researchers repair the damage./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 25% for up to 12 turns

\*Event072 Event: Most of the team on the %Value1% project has taken ill, causing a setback in the project.
\*Event073 Event: The %Value1% project has taken a setback due to most of the research staff becoming infected with an unknown virus.
\*Event074 Event: A virus has infected most of the staff working on the %Value1% project. The resulting setbacks are unavoidable.

\*Event075 Event: A well-respected researcher has disproven several of the theories our research was based on. A major reduction in research has resulted./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 20% for up to 12 turns
\*Event076 Event: Many of our theories on biochemicals have been proven false, causing a drastic slowdown in our overall research./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 20% for up to 12 turns
\*Event077 Event: Our main research data center has been destroyed due to a fire. Our collection of research has slowed drastically as a result./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 20% for up to 12 turns

\*Event078 Event: Destructive AI have gone on a rampage and destroyed years of work in our research facilities. It'll take a long time for us to repair the damage./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 60% for up to 12 turns
\*Event079 Event: The AI at our research collection facility has destroyed all the data. The setback to our research facilities has been devastating./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 60% for up to 12 turns
\*Event080 Event: An AI chip in our research storage facilities has wiped out years of data due to false commands. The effects are devastating./p/p
Research efficiency is decreased by 60% for up to 12 turns

\*Event081 Event: Whispered rumors in %Value1% claimed that local pirates acquired an ancient Antaran star killer. Panic ensued throughout the system./p/p
Unrest is increased by 5% for up to 12 turns
\*Event082 Event: Fear has been caused in the %Value1% system due to rumors of space pirates. The unrest there has increased./p/p
Unrest is increased by 5% for up to 12 turns
\*Event083 Event: Panic has been caused in the %Value1% system by rumors of space pirates operating there. The rumors are causing unrest there./p/p
Unrest is increased by 5% for up to 12 turns

\*Event084 Event: Local starliners have been disappearing in the %Value1% system. It's rumored the space pirates are the cause, and as a result, unrest has increased./p/p
Unrest is increased by 15% for up to 12 turns
\*Event085 Event: Rumors of space pirates destroying ships have been circulating in the %Value1% system, causing unrest./p/p
Unrest is increased by 15% for up to 12 turns
\*Event086 Event: Local rumors point to pirates as the cause of the missing ships in the %Value1% system. Unrest has increased in that area./p/p
Unrest is increased by 15% for up to 12 turns

\*Event087 Event: Pirates in the %Value1% system have threatened to destroy the star. Our military is dealing with the situation, but it's caused unrest to increase./p/p
Unrest is increased by 35% for up to 12 turns
\*Event088 Event: Pirates have threatened several of the planets in the %Value1% system. Panic is sweeping through the system./p/p
Unrest is increased by 35% for up to 12 turns
\*Event089 Event: The %Value1% system has been threatened by pirates, panicking the local citizens. The unrest there has increased./p/p
Unrest is increased by 35% for up to 12 turns

\*Event090 Event: Our diplomatic ability has improved as a result of educational reforms./p/p
Diplomacy gains are increased by 20% for up to 12 turns
\*Event091 Event: Recent improvements made in our educational system have resulted in the advancement of our diplomatic abilities./p/p
Diplomacy gains are increased by 20% for up to 12 turns
\*Event092 Event: Our diplomatic abilities have improved. The reported cause is a better understanding between races due to educational reforms./p/p
Diplomacy gains are increased by 20% for up to 12 turns

\*Event093 Event: A program of exchanging educators with alien societies has led to improvements in our relations with other empires./p/p
Diplomacy gains are increased by 35% for up to 12 turns
\*Event094 Event: Our relations with other empires have improved due to a recent educator exchange reform./p/p
Diplomacy gains are increased by 35% for up to 12 turns
\*Event095 Event: Recent educational improvements have resulted in better relations with other races, due to a better understanding of one another./p/p
Diplomacy gains are increased by 35% for up to 12 turns

\*Event096 Event: An increase in students studying at alien universities greatly increased awareness. As a result, relations with alien races were vastly improved./p/p
Diplomacy gains are increased by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event097 Event: Students studying at alien universities have resulted in an empire-wide appreciation of foreign languages and cultures. Relations with alien races have improved./p/p
Diplomacy gains are increased by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event098 Event: A new student exchange program with other races has improved our relations with other empires./p/p
Diplomacy gains are increased by 50% for up to 12 turns

\*Event105 Event: Buggy translation software has caused diplomatic problems when alien ambassadors became impatient with the device. Our relations have subsequently decreased./p/p
Diplomacy losses are increased by 20% for up to 12 turns
\*Event106 Event: In the middle of our recent diplomatic talks, the translator broke down. The dialog it issued insulted the other ambassador and lowered our relations./p/p
Diplomacy losses are increased by 20% for up to 12 turns
\*Event107 Event: Our relations with several races have been lowered due to faulty translation equipment spewing out gibberish during an important talk./p/p
Diplomacy losses are increased by 20% for up to 12 turns

\*Event108 Event: Alien ambassadors were upset when severe bugs in our translation software caused the machine to display a blue error screen every fifteen minutes./p/p
Diplomacy losses are increased by 30% for up to 12 turns
\*Event109 Event: Our relations with several ambassadors were lowered when our translation equipment broke down, wasting their trip./p/p
Diplomacy losses are increased by 30% for up to 12 turns
\*Event110 Event: Alien ambassadors have become dismayed at us when bugs in our translation equipment caused our recent talks to break down into insults./p/p
Diplomacy losses are increased by 30% for up to 12 turns

\*Event111 Event: A bug in our translation software caused a statement of goodwill to be incorrectly translated as an insult against the ambassador's mother. Diplomatic relations have fallen./p/p
Diplomacy losses are increased by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event112 Event: Diplomatic relations dropped drastically today when our software began insulting the alien ambassadors./p/p
Diplomacy losses are increased by 50% for up to 12 turns
\*Event113 Event: The visiting alien ambassadors left in disgust when the translation software translated a greeting into one of the oldest insults./p/p
Diplomacy losses are increased by 50% for up to 12 turns

\*Event114 Event: An accidental release of experimental nanobots has led to major damage on %Value1%.
\*Event115 Event: Experimental Nanites have escaped from a facility on %Value1%, destroying most of what was in their path.
\*Event116 Event: Major damage has been reported on %Value1% where experimental nanobots escaped into the cities.

\*Event117 Event: Wandering religious zealots were found to be speaking out against our way of life. The problem was contained but has caused unrest on %Value1%./p/p
Unrest is increased by 15 for 1 turn
\*Event118 Event: Unrest has risen on %Value1% since terrorists speaking out against the government had a rally./p/p
Unrest is increased by 15 for 1 turn
\*Event119 Event: The unrest on planet %Value1% has risen due to fanatics causing damage to the starbase there./p/p
Unrest is increased by 15 for 1 turn

\*Event120 Event: The sighting of a rare void crystal in the %Value1% system has caused a dramatic increase in tourism./p/p
Spaceport efficiency is increased by 10% for up to 6 turns
\*Event121 Event: Our space ports in %Value1% are reporting an increase in income due to a rare special event in the skies./p/p
Spaceport efficiency is increased by 10% for up to 6 turns
\*Event122 Event: The %Value1% system has had an increase in income due to a rare space crystal in the system./p/p
Spaceport efficiency is increased by 10% for up to 6 turns

\*Event123 Event: Facilities on %Value1% suffered slight damage due to limited geological disturbances.
\*Event124 Event: A small earthquake on %Value1% has caused some damage to the planet.
\*Event125 Event: A minor earthquake on %Value1% has destroyed some buildings there.

\*Event126 Event: Geologic activity has increased on %Value1%, leading to several major earthquakes. Damage to facilities there appears to be significant.
\*Event127 Event: A major earthquake on %Value1% has destroyed a large portion of the buildings there.
\*Event128 Event: An earthquake has occurred on %Value1%. There appears to have been quite a bit of damage.

\*Event129 Event: Recent deep core mining on %Value1% has led to the release of a dreaded Scath'lok hive. We're currently repairing the damage caused.
\*Event130 Event: A Scath'lok hive was uncovered on %Value1%. The hive attacked the local citizenry and destroyed several of the buildings there.
\*Event131 Event: The release of a Scath'lok hive on planet %Value1% has caused a significant amount of damage on the planet.

\*Event132 Event: Unexpected volcanic activity on %Value1% has caused a series of major earthquakes. Damage reports are expected to be extensive.
\*Event133 Event: A huge earthquake on %Value1% has caused extensive damage to the planet.
\*Event134 Event: Reports indicate catastrophic damage on %Value1% where a major earthquake has occurred.

\*Event135 Event: Devastating tectonic movements have occurred on %Value1%. Major earthquakes continue to rip through the major cities, causing horrific damage.
\*Event136 Event: A series of catastrophic earthquakes has occurred on %Value1% causing major damage to the planet.
\*Event137 Event: A series of volcanic events has occurred on %Value1% destroying a good portion of the planet.

\*Event138 Event: During exploration of a recent planet, Orion technology was found. The discovery wasn't large, but it propelled the %Value1% technology further.
\*Event139 Event: The %Value1% research project has been completed due to a recent discovery.
\*Event140 Event: A recent breakthrough has propelled the %Value1% project to early completion.

\*Event147 Event: At a recent scientific convention, scientists from differing backgrounds found inspiration in other fields of study. Research empire-wide has increased./p/p
Research efficiency is increased by 10% for up to 5 turns
\*Event148 Event: Several recent seminars hosted on our homeworld have advanced several scientific theories. Empire-wide research has increased./p/p
Research efficiency is increased by 10% for up to 5 turns

\*Event149 Event: New theories released from a small cabal of elite scientists have drastically expedited scientific progress. Research has increased./p/p
Research efficiency is increased by 20% for up to 12 turns
\*Event150 Event: A remote scientific outpost recently released findings that helped promote research in several fields, resulting in an empire-wide increase in research./p/p
Research efficiency is increased by 20% for up to 12 turns

\*EvSysMod System Event
\*EvPltMod Planetary Event
\*EvEmpMod Empire Event

\\Unused Events
\\*Event099 Event: In a targeted strike by terrorists against our command fortress, the leader %Value1% has been wounded. They're not expected to survive.
\\*Event100 Event: Sir! There's been an accident. %Value1% has been wounded and is not expected to survive.
\\*Event101 Event: One of your leaders in the high council has been wounded. %Value1% is hurt badly.

\\*Event102 Event: In a successful targeted strike against his command vessel, the leader, %Value1%, of our forces has been killed.
\\*Event103 Event: The leader %Value1% has suffered a horrible accident. They're not expected to survive.
\\*Event104 Event: A terrorist spy has infiltrated our command post. %Value1% has been poisoned and isn't expected to survive the night.

\\*Event141 Event: Reports indicate that several divisions of our troops have deserted due to the horrible attrition of a recent battle.
\\*Event142 Event: A number of reports surfaced recently of unrest on a frontier world. Due to dangerous weapons testing, several divisions of ground troops have deserted.
\\*Event143 Event: A number of our troops have deserted recently. It will take time to replace them.

\\*Event144 Event: Reports indicate several losses in our ground corps stationed on border worlds. Time will tell how long it will take to replace them.
\\*Event145 Event: Several corps of our best troops deserted after a horrific battle.
\\*Event146 Event: Due to reports of deadly enemy biological weapons, several ground troop corps have deserted their posts.


