\*LDRSTITL PERSONNEL

\*LDRSAPLD LEADERS
\*LDRSAPES ESPIONAGE

\*LDRSCOUN Leaders in your High Council: %value%
\*LDRSPHCO Your High Council is empty.

\*LDRSTRCO Cost

\*LDRSDISL DISMISS SELECTED LEADER
\*LDRSDISC CANCEL DISMISS ORDER

\*LDRSSELI SELECTED LEADER INFO

\*LDRSPHNM Name
\*LDRSPHLW Long-Winded Placeholder text.

\*LDRSESMC CURRENT SPY MAINTENANCE COST:

\*LDRSESPR SPY RECRUITMENT
\*LDRSESPT SPY TRAINING
\*LDRSEPMC Primary Mission Circle:
\*LDRSERTS RECRUIT THIS SPY TYPE
\*LDRSECTA Current Training Activity:
\*LDRSETRC Primary Mission Circle
\*LDRSETRT Time Remaining
\*LDRSEDES DELETE SELECTED
\*LDRSEDCA RESUME TRAINING

\*LDRSEAIF AGENTS IN THE FIELD
\*LDRSELOS LIST OF SPIES

\*LDRSEAGT Agent
\*LDRSEAST Status
\*LDRSEAMS Mission Circle
\*LDRSESAI SELECTED AGENT INFORMATION
\*LDRSEAGI AGENT INSERTION
\*LDRSEACN Agent Code Name:
\*LDRSEACL Current Activity:
\*LDRSEORD Orders:
\*LDRSEPRC Primary Circle:
\*LDRSECLO Cloak:
\*LDRSELUK Luck:
\*LDRSEDAG Dagger:
\*LDRSELOY Loyalty:
\*LDRSERET Retire Agent?

\*LDRSESNI Internal Security
\*LDRSESIN Inserted, %value%
\*LDRSESIM Imprisoned, %value%

\*LDRSEOIN Insert, %value%
\*LDRSEORC Recall
\*LDRSEORT Retire
\*LDRSEONC No Change

\*LDRSEEMP EMPIRE
\*LDRSENIA NUMBER OF INFILTRATED AGENTS

\*LDRSEIAS Insert an agent into the selected empire?
\*LDRSEIAG INSERT AGENT
\*LDRSEREC RECALL AGENTS
\*LDRSECRE CANCEL RECALL

\\Espionage Mission Circle Descriptions
\!EsMCi
\-ERROR!  This is NOT an option for espionage missions.
\-Military Intelligence.  An oxymoron?  Perhaps.  But that will be the job of this recruit. Military spies destroy anything they can get their hands on, from ships to buildings and even the occasional production line.
\-A spy of this category will infiltrate political circles, because there's obviously not enough double-crossing, backstabbing, trickery and sneaking around already. These spies concentrate all their efforts on assassination attempts of other high level leaders.
\-This spy will be of the economic type, and will fanatically finagle with finances and funds for fun. His primary duties will include disrupting the economic activities of opposing empires by disrupting trade routes and destroying economic buildings.
\-Spies focusing their duties in this circle cause fear throughout enemy empires by destroying recreation centers and causing general hysteria.
\-A diplomatic spy will introduce his special brand of tomfoolery into the embassy by destroying government buildings.
\-Scientific spies masquerade as flunky physics students and make their way into the laboratory through whatever means necessary. Once there they disrupt projects, destroy science buildings and steal technologies.
\-Administrative spies will do their part to make the administration of target empires a mess.  Although not nearly as effective as good old-fashioned government bureaucracy, you gotta hand it to them for trying.
\-Intelligence.  This spy will be a spy who spies on spies, who may also be, though won't necessarily, spying right back at them.
