\*OSPNMTTL Senate Membership (Observer) for %empire%
\*OSPFMTTL Senate Membership for %empire%
\*OSPCMTTL Praise %empire%
\*OSPCDTTL Condemn %empire%
\*OSPESTTL Economic Sanctions against %empire%
\*OSPEETTL Economic Embargo against %empire%
\*OSPMRTTL Senate Membership Reduction for %empire%
\*OSPDITTL Diplomatic Isolation for %empire%
\*OSPXSTTL Expulsion from the Senate for %empire%
\*OSPLWTTL Declare Limited War against %empire%
\*OSPTWTTL Declare Total War against %empire%
\*OSPCPTTL Cease Punishment against %empire%
\*OSPCSTTL Cease Sanctions against %empire%
\*OSPCETTL Cease Embargo against %empire%
\*OSPCRTTL Reverse Membership Reduction for %empire%
\*OSPCLTTL Cease Limited War against %empire%
\*OSPCTTTL Cease Total War against %empire%

\*OSPNMPNM Senate Membership (Observer)
\*OSPFMPNM Senate Membership (Full)
\*OSPCMPNM Praise
\*OSPCDPNM Condemnation
\*OSPESPNM Economic Sanctions
\*OSPEEPNM Economic Embargo
\*OSPMRPNM Senate Membership Reduction
\*OSPDIPNM Diplomatic Isolation
\*OSPXSPNM Expulsion from the Senate
\*OSPLWPNM Declare Limited War
\*OSPTWPNM Declare Total War
\*OSPCPPNM Cease Punishment
\*OSPCSPNM Cease Sanctions
\*OSPCEPNM Cease Embargo
\*OSPCRPNM Reverse Membership Reduction
\*OSPCLPNM Cease Limited War
\*OSPCTPNM Cease Total War

\*OSPNMCLS CLOSING: The purpose of this enactment is to grant non-voting membership to %empire%.
\*OSPFMCLS This Act has been proposed to recognize the technical advancement, cultural achievements and growing importance of the %empire% Empire.  We believe that with the wisdom and knowledge possessed by the %empire%s, their presence will have a long-lasting and positive impact on the future decisions and rulings of the Orion Senate, and are proud to sponsor them.
\*OSPCMCLS This Act has been proposed to proclaim the %empire% Empire as an example that all Member Empires should strive to imitate.  Their selfless acts to assist minor Magnate Empires and continued positive relationships with their galactic neighbors are commendable, and worthy of official recognition.
\*OSPCDCLS This Act has been proposed to hold the %empire% accountable for their appalling crimes.  Everything from their brutal treatment of minor races under their control, to the frequent border violations and excessive spying on peaceful neighbors are setting a disgraceful precedent.  It is therefore necessary to give the %empire% official notice of the need for immediate corrective changes.
\*OSPESCLS The alarming attitudes and disgraceful actions of the %empire% have disturbed the tranquility of some of their galactic neighbors.  This Act has been placed before the Orion Senate for Members to make a minor adjustment to their Trade Agreements with the %empire% as an appropriate inducement to modify both their actions and their attitudes.
\*OSPEECLS In an effort to encourage improved behavior by the %empire% in dealing with their neighbors, all Member Empires are asked to make substantial modifications to their Trade Agreements to illustrate to the %empire% that they must change their ways.
\*OSPMRCLS CLOSING: The purpose of this enactment is to reduce the membership of %empire% to non-voting status.
\*OSPDICLS Having significantly offended many of the Orion Senate Members by continually pestering them with pathetic, useless and totally improper Trade Agreements and Treaties, (Does Anybody want to accept trade agreements involving old copies of Galactic Civilization? or Treaties promising NOT to make funny faces when others are speaking?) it has therefore been proposed that through this act, Senate Members limit contact with the %empire%.
\*OSPXSCLS Through their words and actions the delegation from the %empire% have seriously insulted and deeply offended other Orion Senate Member delegations.  Offended delegates met and held extensive internal discussions to explore alternatives, but were unable to find any that they felt were adequate.  Therefore it is with deep regret that this Expulsion act has been proposed.  Hopefully the %empire% can appoint more respectful delegates if they are nominated for Senate Membership again. /p/p(Besides, they smell VERY bad and nobody wants to sit beside them at the conferences.)
\*OSPLWCLS Apparently neither Official Disapproval nor the enactment of Trade Reductions have persuaded the %empire% to change their malicious way of life and live in harmony with their galactic neighbors.  This Act proposes that where strong words and negative financial incentives have failed, the time has come for corrective physical measures to be implemented.  Surely the use of force will cause the %empire% to see that they MUST make every effort to live in harmony with the other Members of the Galaxy.
\*OSPTWCLS The %empire% Empire have shown through their actions that they are not willing to abide by the Lawful Requests and Rulings of the Orion Senate.  Additionally, their continual violent assaults on their peaceful and weaker neighbors, the total decimation of those who are likely to disagree with them and blatant attempts to take control of the entire galaxy, have proven that there is no other option but the total elimination of the %empire%s from the galaxy.   This Act may be Our Last Best Hope for Peace.  (After they are removed of course.)
\*OSPCPCLS CLOSING: The purpose of this enactment is to cease punishment against %empire%.
\*OSPCSCLS It now appears that the %empire% have made an attempt to live peaceably with their neighbors.  Therefore some Orion Senate Members have proposed that Trade Agreement reductions with the %empire% be eliminated.  (Besides, they are not That much trouble, and we really need the cash.)
\*OSPCECLS The %empire% have agreed to change their ways, and made some effort to be less upsetting to their galactic neighbors.  This Act has been proposed to require all Members of the Orion Senate to fully restore, to their original levels, all Trade Agreements with the %empire%.  Once again the Orion Senate has shown that problems can have diplomatic solutions, and that resorting to violent conflict is not only undesirable, but unnecessary as well.  
\*OSPCRCLS CLOSING: The purpose of this enactment is to reverse %empire%'s Senate membership reduction.
\*OSPCLCLS Sometimes armed conflict is the only course of action that will produce a desired result.  However, it is crucial for diplomats that, once the desired result has (or at least Appears likely to have) been achieved, they make every effort to stop all hostilities.  Since the %empire% have promised to stop harassing their neighbors, and have withdrawn a few ships from the border, this Act proposes an end to all minor conflicts between Senate Members and the %empire%.
\*OSPCTCLS The Orion Senate believes that the %empire% now fully understand that they must behave as a civilized Empire and respect the territory and rights of their galactic neighbors.  It is regretful that so many of their beings and worlds had to discover the terrors of war, after having inflicted such terrors on other Empires, before the %empire% renounced their former campaign of galactic domination.  Therefore this Act is proposed to cease waging all warfare (except wars waged for religious reasons) against the beings of the %empire%.

\*OSPNMPRP If passed this act will grant non-voting membership to %empire%.
\*OSPFMPRP If passed this act will grant full membership to %empire%.
\*OSPCMPRP If passed this act will praise %empire% for their great deeds.
\*OSPCDPRP If passed this act will condemn %empire% for their crimes.
\*OSPESPRP If passed this act will impose economic sanctions against %empire%.
\*OSPEEPRP If passed this act will impose an economic embargo against %empire%.
\*OSPMRPRP If passed this act will reduce the membership of %empire% to non-voting status.
\*OSPDIPRP If passed this act will punish %empire% with diplomatic isolation.
\*OSPXSPRP If passed this act will expel %empire% from the Orion Senate.
\*OSPLWPRP If passed this act will declare a limited war against %empire%.
\*OSPTWPRP If passed this act will declare total war against %empire%.
\*OSPCPPRP If passed this act will cease punishment against %empire%.
\*OSPCSPRP If passed this act will cease economic sanctions against %empire%.
\*OSPCEPRP If passed this act will cease economic embargoes against %empire%.
\*OSPCRPRP If passed this act will reverse the Senate membership reduction ruling against %empire%.
\*OSPCLPRP If passed this act will end the declaration of limited war against %empire%.
\*OSPCTPRP If passed this act will end the declaration of total war against %empire%.

\*OSPNMSUM This act grants non-voting member status to an Empire.
\*OSPFMSUM This act grants full member status to an Empire.
\*OSPCMSUM Having the Senate Praise an Empire is a great way for all Members of the Senate to get a small boost in relations with that Empire.  If passed, all Members of the Senate will gain Current Relations points with the target Empire.
\*OSPCDSUM The opposite of Praise, if a Condemnation bill is passed, all Members of the Senate have their Current Relations with the target Empire reduced by a small amount.
\*OSPESSUM A Senate Economic Sanctions bill will cause all Members of the Senate to declare Economic Sanctions on the target Empire. Sanctions reduce all trade income for the target Empire.
\*OSPEESUM A Senate Economic Embargo bill will cause all Members of the Senate to declare an Economic Embargo on the target Empire.  An Economic Embargo drastically reduces trade with the target Empire.
\*OSPMRSUM Senate Membership Reduction will reduce the target Empire to non-voting Senate Member status.
\*OSPDISUM A Diplomatic Isolation bill, if passed, will have all Empires break diplomatic contact with the target Empire. 
\*OSPXSSUM An Expulsion From The Senate bill will expel an Empire from the Orion Senate if passed.  That Empire may later be readmitted to the Senate, of course.
\*OSPLWSUM Declare Limited War will cause all Members of the Senate to declare war on the target Empire for a short time. The war may continue on its own after the duration is over.
\*OSPTWSUM Declare Total War will cause all Members of the Senate to declare war on the target Empire. Generally, these wars will last longer than the Limited War option, though not always. The war may continue on its own after the duration is over.
\*OSPCPSUM The Cease Punishment bill seeks to repeal any existing punishments the Senate has levied on a target Empire, such as an Embargo or Limited War.
\*OSPCSSUM Cease Economic Sanctions seeks to end Economic Sanctions against a target Empire.
\*OSPCESUM Cease Economic Embargoes seeks to end Economic Embargoes against a target Empire.
\*OSPCRSUM Reverse Senate Membership Reduction will restore the target Senate-Observer Empire to full Senate Member status.
\*OSPCLSUM Cease Limited War if passed will end all wars, except total war or holy war, between Senate Members and the target Empire.
\*OSPCTSUM Cease Total War will end all wars, except holy war, between Senate Members and the target Empire.

\*SenLaw01 Senate Peace Accord
\*SenLaw02 Anti-cloning Initiative
\*SenLaw03 Spaceport Taxation
\*SenLaw04 Senate Audit
\*SenLaw05 Senate Research Program
\*SenLaw06 Inter-Empire Holiday Declaration
\*SenLaw07 Orion Recycling Initiative
\*SenLaw08 Senate Farming Subsidies
\*SenLaw09 Senate Mining Subsidies
\*SenLaw10 Standardized Working Hours
\*SenLaw11 Natural Preservation Initiative
\*SenLaw12 Travel and Tourism Initiative
\*SenLaw13 Senate Research Subsidies
\*SenLaw14 Humane Labor Law
\*SenLaw15 Orion Summit Meeting
\*SenLaw16 Homeland Defense Bill
\*SenLaw17 Forced Labor Reparations
\*SenLaw18 Anti-Spying Initiative
\*SenLaw19 Weapon Inspections Referendum
\*SenLaw20 Ban on Nuclear Weapons
\*SenLaw21 Ban on Biological Weapons
\*SenLaw22 Ban on Chemical Weapons
\*SenLaw23 Jump Lane Tracking Law
\*SenLaw24 Galactic Relief Fund
\*SenLaw25 Orion Database Standardization
\*SenLaw26
\*SenLaw27
\*SenLaw28
\*SenLaw29
 
\*LW01TITL Senate Peace Accord
\*LW02TITL Anti-cloning Initiative
\*LW03TITL Spaceport Taxation
\*LW04TITL Senate Audit
\*LW05TITL Senate Research Program
\*LW06TITL Inter-Empire Holiday Declaration
\*LW07TITL Orion Recycling Initiative
\*LW08TITL Senate Farming Subsidies
\*LW09TITL Senate Mining Subsidies
\*LW10TITL Standardized Working Hours
\*LW11TITL Natural Preservation Initiative
\*LW12TITL Travel and Tourism Initiative
\*LW13TITL Senate Research Subsidies
\*LW14TITL Humane Labor Law
\*LW15TITL Orion Summit Meeting
\*LW16TITL Homeland Defense Bill
\*LW17TITL Forced Labor Reparations
\*LW18TITL Anti-Spying Initiative
\*LW19TITL Weapon Inspections Referendum
\*LW20TITL Ban on Nuclear Weapons
\*LW21TITL Ban on Biological Weapons
\*LW22TITL Ban on Chemical Weapons
\*LW23TITL Jump Lane Tracking Law
\*LW24TITL Galactic Relief Fund
\*LW25TITL Orion Database Standardization
\*LW26TITL
\*LW27TITL
\*LW28TITL
\*LW29TITL

\*LW01CLS The intention of the Senate Peace Accord is to endorse and encourage Member Empires' efforts to gain a better understanding of one another.  With understanding comes trust, and as trust increases, tensions will be reduced.  Thus reduced tensions will eventually develop between all Senate Member Empires.  Perhaps one day soon, war can once again become a thing of the past.
\*LW02CLS The Anti-cloning Initiative's goal is to reject and refuse clones the legal status of living sentient beings.  Sentient beings without legal status Cannot be employed by nor receive services from any official DEA organizations.  This initiative does not remove the legal status of existing clones, only future clones produced after the bill's passage.  Medical Cloning, to provide body parts for injuries and illness, is not affected as long as it is done only in approved "Cloning Complex" tech centers.
\*LW03CLS The purpose of the Spaceport Taxation Law is to simplify and reduce the exceedingly immense number of importation and exportation tax rules, rates and regulations between worlds.  The current system wastes an enormous amount of time and funds as Spaceport officials struggle to keep and maintain accurate records of the rates and regulations between multiple worlds, systems and empires.
\*LW04CLS The stated purpose of the Senate Audit is to evaluate the funding and accounting procedures in use by all Senate Member Empires for construction of planetary improvements and shipbuilding.  In actuality, all Member Empires know the Audit's underlying function is to investigate and uncover any evidence of involvement by Senate Members in the system piracy attacks and smuggling rings that have been plaguing the galaxy for far too long.
\*LW05CLS The Senate Research Program is an Inter-Empire research project of massive proportions operating under the direction and control of the New Orions.  The project's ambition is the development of a radically new Seventh school of technology that will produce major benefits in the form of new techs to all Senate Members equally.  All Member Empires will donate a small portion of their research which will be redirected to the project.  As payment the Orion Senate will supply a superior market price for any rare minerals produced while the program is in effect.
\*LW06CLS This Declaration creates a holiday in recognition of the New Orions' early effort to remove the cheese from the galaxy.  Their systematic destruction of the Darlok, Bulrathi, Mrrshan, Elerian and Alkari homeworlds showed the Galaxy that cheese has no place in it.  To honor this day, all businesses will be closed to allow every sentient being to join in the grand and glorious celebrations planned to praise the New Orions for their noteworthy accomplishment. 
\*LW07CLS This Law creates the 'Significant Consumer Recycling Achievements Program' (SCRAP) in all Member Empires.  The function of SCRAP is to encourage the populace and government of each Member Empire to make extensive changes in their recycling habits to ensure that all usable materials are recycled. The effect of this effort will reduce pollution and increase the scrap values of all buildings and ships scrapped by an Empire.  Unfortunately, there are costs associated with this, which is reflected in slightly increased maintenance costs.
\*LW08CLS The Senate Farming Subsidies Act is an attempt by the Orion Senate to make up for the shortcomings of some Member Empires due to their inability to provide sufficient bioharvest output to support their population. (We won't embarrass them by mentioning names.)  Funds will be collected from all Member Empires and used to create subsidies for Bioharvesting in all Member Empires.  The subsidies will be used to fund administrative changes to the Bioharvest DEAs with the ultimate goal of noticeably increasing their output.
\*LW09CLS The Senate Mining Subsidies is an attempt by the Orion Senate to make up for the shortcomings of some Member Empires due to their inability to provide sufficient Mineral output to support their Industry and/or population. (We Were going to mention names, but at the last moment decided not to.)  Funds will be collected from all Member Empires and used to create subsidies for Mining in all Member Empires.  The subsidies will be used to fund administrative changes to the Mining DEAs with the ultimate goal of noticeably increasing their output.
\*LW10CLS The enactment of Standardized Working Hours (SWH) is an attempt by the Orion Senate to remedy a situation in which some Member Empires are enforcing employment of all sentient beings for up to 75%% of a standard "day/night" period.  Thus leaving their population without sufficient time for personal responsibilities / clan duties / hive functions.  SWH will set the maximum length of employment to 66%% of a standard "day/night" period.  Studies show that even with the reduced hours, productivity should slightly increase due to employee satisfaction alone.  (Besides, some of them have been talking about Unionizing and we DON'T want to go there!)
\*LW11CLS The goal of the Natural Preservation Initiative is to attempt to save as many of the currently existing natural habitats of jungle wilderness, birthing swamps and methane seas remaining in the galaxy.  Too many Member Empires, upon colonization of new planets, promptly commence terraforming operations of those planets.  Thus forever destroying the original natural state of the planetary environment.  By imposing additional administrative fees on all terraforming operations, the Senate hopes that all Member Empires will lessen the terraforming they order performed, and preserve as many of the planetary regions as possible in their natural state.
\*LW12CLS The Orion Senate hopes that the Travel and Tourism Initiative will result in additional contact between Member Empires from the influx of new tourists visiting their worlds, while their own population tours and visits the worlds of other Empires.  It is thought that this will lead to a better understanding between Empires.  The Initiative encourages tourism among Member Empires, by promoting the ancient ruins, cultural sites, shopping opportunities and natural wonders to be found on many worlds.  The "objective" of the initiative is to reduce tensions across the Galaxy.
\*LW13CLS The Senate Research Subsidies is an attempt by the Orion Senate to make up for the shortcomings of some Member Empires due to their inability to generate sufficient Research output to keep pace technologically with the rest of the Galaxy. (There is no need to mention names, EVERYBODY knows who you are.)  Funds will be collected from all Member Empires and used to create subsidies for Research in all Member Empires.  The subsidies will be used to fund administrative changes to the Research DEAs with the ultimate goal of noticeably increasing their output.
\*LW14CLS The Humane Labor Law will enforce standard hiring and employment procedures in all Member Empires. The deliberate hiring of undocumented and/or poorly documented sentient beings by employers allows the employers to underpay and overwork them.  By closely checking the documents and backgrounds of employees and requiring employers to maintain accurate records of employment, the Senate hopes to eliminate undocumented sentient beings and false paperwork.
\*LW15CLS If convened, the Orion Summit Meeting will endeavor to develop improved relationships between Member Empires through a lengthy series of committee conferences.  These conferences will cover a wide variety of subjects ranging from Anti-Piracy Co-operation to Xenophobia Reduction.  It is anticipated that this Summit Meeting will allow Member Empires to peaceably solve issues troubling them through quiet thoughtful discussion, rather than through violent armed conflict.
\*LW16CLS The Homeland Defense Bill is a drive to increase the internal security awareness of all Member Empires.  The bill's intention is to organize and educate the sentient beings of each Empire World to be more aware and alert to the possible dangers of other empires.  This will be done by the creation of a new Department to manage and coordinate the education plans and introduce the organizational groups needed.  With the increasing popular support for the military expected from the increased awareness, costs for Fleet Maintenance are forecast to drop significantly.
\*LW17CLS While disputed by most Senate Members, enough support has been raised despite objections to introduce the Forced Labor Reparations Bill.  Proclaiming that many descendants of former involuntary workers have been adversely affected by their ancestors' status, the Reparations Bill hopes to compensate them financially to help their current situation.  Opponents of the bill fear that descendants of Current FLUs may one day also request Reparations.
\*LW18CLS The Anti-Spying Initiative is designed to eliminate the scourge of spying by Orion Senate Members.  While the Senate does recognize that Data Gathering by spies has a long established "history", many Members are using spies not just for Data gathering, but also encouraging spies to embark on missions devoted to committing assassinations, destroying buildings, sabotaging production and inciting unrest in other empires.   To oppose this, the Senate proposes requiring extensive data exchange programs - such as current ID forging techniques, advance passenger ship manifests and known enemy spy lists - between Member Empires.  This will significantly increase the chance of catching spies.
\*LW19CLS At last cycle's Orion Senate gathering, one of the subcommittees drafted and approved the "Illegal Research Events and Activities List with Yearly update for Weapons and other Illicit Lines of Labor" (IREALLYWILL) and all Member Empires signed and certified that they were NOT researching any of the illegal weapons on the list.  Recently there has been an increase in accusations between Members of illegal weapons research by some Members, however no one has been able to provide conclusive proof of such accusations.  As a result, the Orion Senate has proposed a Weapon Inspections Referendum.  The Referendum will authorize inspection teams composed of inspectors provided by each Member Empire to perform inspections of research and production lines to ensure total compliance with the IREALLYWILL.
\*LW20CLS The Orion Senate decrees that the use of Nuclear Weapons of mass destruction during ground warfare is An Abomination against sentient beings and Nature.  These devices, when used, kill virtually all life and destroy the planetary environment.  The Senate therefore imposes a Ban on their use during Ground Combat.  Any Member using such devices will be condemned by the Senate on GNN. (Galactic News Network: "When You Want to Know What's Happening")  Potentially drastic increases in political unrest can be expected. /p[Advertising paid for by GNN]
\*LW21CLS The Orion Senate declares that using Biological Weapons of mass destruction during ground warfare has Extremely Adverse Effects on sentient beings and Nature.  These devices, when used, kill virtually all intelligent life and can damage the planetary environment.  The Senate therefore imposes a Ban on their use during Ground Combat.  Any Member using such devices will be condemned by the Senate on GNN. (Galactic News Network: "When You Absolutely Have to Know What Happened Today")  Potentially drastic increases in political unrest can be expected. /p[Advertising paid for by GNN]
\*LW22CLS The Orion Senate decrees that the use of Chemical Weapons of mass destruction during ground warfare is Potentially Harmful to sentient beings and Nature.  These devices, when used, kill most forms of advanced life and seriously damage the planetary environment.  The Senate therefore imposes a Ban on their use during Ground Combat.  Any Member using such devices will be condemned by the Senate on GNN. (Galactic News Network: "What Happened? If You Watched You Would Know")  Potentially drastic increases in political unrest can be expected. /p[Advertising paid for by GNN]
\*LW23CLS The Jump Lane Tracking Law has been proposed as part of the Orion Senate's continuing attempt to combat the ever-growing hazard of Pirate activities.  The increase in raids on shipping near planetary systems by pirate ships and the resulting loss of commercial trading ships has increased unrest on planets throughout the galaxy.   In an effort to combat the problem, this Law will require all ships in the Orion sector to be equipped with small transponders making instant identification of ships and their owners upon being sighted.  Any ship NOT carrying a transponder will be assumed to be a pirate and may be targeted and destroyed by ships of all Member Empires.
\*LW24CLS The Galactic Relief Fund is an inspired new Senate campaign designed to alleviate the suffering, misery and poor social circumstances in which some of the less fortunate sentient beings in all Member Empires of the Orion sector occasionally find themselves, through a series of charity relief programs.  While these programs do NOT provide any direct financial aid to these unfortunates, various programs have been designed to provide for all their needs, such as corrective education, advanced training, character re-development, medical assistance, behavioral rehabilitation, substance abuse treatment and recreational social contact.  With ALL that we are providing them how could they be unhappy?!
\*LW25CLS Driven by the Micro-Sun Galactic Corporation, the Orion Database Standardization is an attempt by business leaders throughout the Orion Sector to make trade simpler.  Their plan involves the implementation of rigid packing design specifications (that make manufacturing only a little more difficult) and scrapping the planned upgrade in government specifications, reverting instead to the previous, though outdated, government specifications (which had fewer governmental inspection requirements). Business leaders are forecasting that the benefits in trade will exceed the expected reduction in manufacturing output.
\*LW26CLS
\*LW27CLS
\*LW28CLS
\*LW29CLS

\*LW01PROP If passed, while this law is in effect, Empires which are at war are more likely to end those wars and new wars are much less likely to break out.
\*LW02PROP If passed, this Law will make reproduction by cloning illegal, reducing the growth rate in all Senate Empires but will lower unrest to a similar extent
\*LW03PROP If passed, the Spaceport Taxation Law will set unified tax rates for all spaceports belonging to Senate Members, with the net effect of increasing Spaceport revenues by a significant amount.
\*LW04PROP If passed, each Senate Member will undergo a lengthy and in-depth internal audit to ensure compliance with standard accounting practices and procedures. Unfortunately, due to the hidden purpose, this is a very expensive process and requires a great deal of overhead and bureaucracy, which increases the Heavy Foot of Government of all Empires in the Senate for the length of the audit, but the increased efficiency of taxation increases tax income as well.
\*LW05PROP If passed, the New Orions will begin an Inter-Empire research program.  This will reduce the research capacity of all Member Empires and raise the value of rare minerals generated.
\*LW06PROP If passed, a Holiday will be observed on all planets of all Civilizations belonging to the Senate. The closing of business for the day reduces Manufacturing capacity and tax revenue, but the celebration reduces unrest as well.
\*LW07PROP If passed, this Initiative will increase pollution absorbtion and funds recovered from scrapping units and structures, but maintenance costs are increased due to the addition of the numerous multi-section waste containers and disposal routes that must be installed.
\*LW08PROP If passed, the Senate Farming Subsidies will slightly increase Bioharvest efficiency as well as the value of any rare Bioharvest output while slightly lowering income from taxes at the Empire level.
\*LW09PROP If passed, the Senate Mining Subsidies will slightly increase Mining efficiency as well as the value of any rare Mineral output while slightly lowering income from taxes at the Empire level.
\*LW10PROP If passed, Standardized Working Hours will only slightly increase the efficiency of Manufacturing, and reduce Unrest.  However, one complication, unforeseen by the Senate but immediately obvious to the Managers of Industry DEAs, is that by cutting back on pollution controls they can greatly increase production to ensure they are above previous Manufacturing efficiency levels. Thus Pollution cleanup costs will increase.
\*LW11PROP If passed, this Law will create disincentives for Terraforming, in the form of tariffs which increase the cost of all Terraforming projects.
\*LW12PROP If passed, the Travel and Tourism Initiative encourages tourism among Member Empires, increasing the efficiency of Recreation DEAs.  However, the increased burden on Space Ports and ships from tourism increases the cost of Fleet Maintenance.  Unfortunately, most travel agents feel the reduced tensions will not occur, due to the "Ugly American" syndrome exhibited by most tourists on new worlds.
\*LW13PROP If passed, the Senate Research Subsidies will slightly increase Research efficiency while slightly lowering income from taxes at the Empire level.
\*LW14PROP If passed, the Humane Labor Law increases the chances of catching spies since all governments will have a more accurate database of workers.  However, as the workers are under closer observation, they tend to be less creative, resulting in a decrease in research.
\*LW15PROP If passed, the Orion Summit Meeting will promote better understanding and reduce tensions between all Member Empires resulting in an immediate increase in Current Relations.
\*LW16PROP If passed, the Homeland Defense Bill will decrease all fleet maintenance costs.  However, the increased bureaucracy involved decreases spy defenses.
\*LW17PROP If passed, the Forced Labor Reparations Bill will cause a one time payment of 1000 AU to descendants of former involuntary workers to be deducted from all Member Empires' Treasuries.
\*LW18PROP If passed, the Anti-Spying Initiative will make stopping spies more likely.  However, the Intergalactic Spy Union (ISpyU) is protesting this action and plans to impose a Mandatory Wage Increase for all spies if the Initiative is passed. This will raise the cost of training, resulting in lowered offensive abilities.
\*LW19PROP If passed, the Weapon Inspections Referendum allows a panel of Senate approved weapon inspectors to make surprise visits to a Member Empire's weapon development facilities to check for illegal weapons research.  In practice, it simply makes keeping secrets more difficult, and Weapons Inspector is a perfect cover for a spy.  As a result, Spy Defenses are decreased and foreign spies are more likely to infiltrate an Empire successfully.
\*LW20PROP If passed, the Ban on Nuclear Weapons Bill will make it illegal to use Nuclear weapons of mass destruction during ground warfare.  Empires that violate this will be publicly condemned by the Senate, and suffer 50% greater Unrest penalties than normal when using Nuclear Weapons.
\*LW21PROP If passed, the Ban on Biological Weapons Bill will make it illegal to use Biological weapons of mass destruction during ground warfare.  Empires that violate this will be publicly condemned by the Senate, and suffer 50% greater Unrest penalties than normal when using Biological Weapons.
\*LW22PROP If passed, the Ban on Chemical Weapons Bill will make it illegal to use Chemical weapons of mass destruction during ground warfare.  Empires that violate this will be publicly condemned by the Senate, and suffer 50% greater Unrest penalties than normal when using Chemical Weapons.
\*LW23PROP If passed, the Jump Lane Tracking Law will install identification transponders on all ships.  One unexpected benefit to these transponders is that it makes ships carrying them visible 50% sooner along Jump Lanes.
\*LW24PROP If passed, the Galactic Relief Fund will reduce all Member Empires' empire-wide tax revenues to fund the programs.  One benefit of the programs, the improved situation for the unfortunates will reduce Unrest and all Members will have Current Relations improve slightly as everyone's social situation improves.
\*LW25PROP If passed, the Orion Database Standardization Law will make trade simpler. In effect, it slightly decreases Manufacturing Efficiency while increasing Space Port efficiency.  Fewer inspections will also reduce the Heavy Foot of Government.
\*LW26PROP
\*LW27PROP
\*LW28PROP
\*LW29PROP

\*LW01SUM Decreases the chances of going to War for the duration of the agreement.
\*LW02SUM Decreases population growth rate and unrest by 10%%.
\*LW03SUM Increases Spaceport revenue by roughly 20%%.
\*LW04SUM Increases the Heavy Foot of Government by 20%% and tax revenues by 10%% for all Empires for the duration of the audit.
\*LW05SUM Increases the sale value of Rare minerals by 3%% and decreases Research Capacity in Member Empires by 2%%.
\*LW06SUM Decreases Manufacturing Capacity by 10%%, decreases Unrest by 20%%, and decreases tax revenue by 10%%.
\*LW07SUM Increases Pollution absorbtion by 30%%, increases Scrap Values by 15%%, and increases Maintenance costs by 20%%.
\*LW08SUM Increases Bioharvest Efficiency by 1, increases Bioharvest Rare value by 15%%, and decreases Empire-wide taxes by 5%%.
\*LW09SUM Increases Mining Efficiency by 1, increases Mining Rare value by 15%%, and Decreases Empire-wide taxes by 5%%.
\*LW10SUM Increases Manufacturing Efficiency by 2, Decreases Unrest by 5, and increases Pollution clean up costs by 15%%.
\*LW11SUM Increases Terraforming costs by 25%%.
\*LW12SUM Increases Recreation DEA efficiency by 3 and increases Fleet Maintenance costs by 10%%.
\*LW13SUM Increases Research Efficiency by 3 and decreases Empire-wide taxes by 5%%.
\*LW14SUM Increases Spy Defense by 20 and Decreases Research Efficiency by 25%%.
\*LW15SUM Increases Current Relations by 20.
\*LW16SUM Decreases Fleet Maintenance by 20%% and Decreases Spy Defense by 10.
\*LW17SUM Subtracts 1000 AU from the Empire Treasury.
\*LW18SUM Increases Spy Repel by 10 and decreases Spy Offense by 10.
\*LW19SUM Decreases Spy Defense by 10 and increases Spy Insert success by 10.
\*LW20SUM Increases Unrest from using Nuclear weapons by 50%%.
\*LW21SUM Increases Unrest from using Biological weapons by 50%%.
\*LW22SUM Increases Unrest from using Chemical weapons by 50%%.
\*LW23SUM Increases the range of Planetary Sensors by 50%%.
\*LW24SUM Decreases Empire taxes by 10%%, decreases Unrest by 10, and improves Current Relations by +1 each turn.
\*LW25SUM Decreases Manufacturing Efficiency by 10%%, decreases Heavy Foot of Government by 10%%, and Increases Space Port Efficiency by 20%%.
\*LW26SUM
\*LW27SUM
\*LW28SUM
\*LW29SUM

\*LW01SSIT The Senate Peace Accord has been ratified.
\*LW02SSIT The Anti-cloning Initiative is now in effect.
\*LW03SSIT Spaceport Taxation is now being regulated by the Orion Senate.
\*LW04SSIT Senate Auditors from New Orion have arrived and are examining our accounts in accordance with the Audit.
\*LW05SSIT The Senate Research Program has begun.
\*LW06SSIT A New Orion Holiday has been declared.
\*LW07SSIT The Orion Recycling Initiative has been passed.
\*LW08SSIT The Orion Senate Farming Subsidies have been enacted.
\*LW09SSIT The Orion Senate Mining Subsidies have been enacted.
\*LW10SSIT Standardized Working Hours has been ratified.
\*LW11SSIT The Natural Preservation Initiative has been ratified.
\*LW12SSIT The Travel and Tourism Initiative has been passed.
\*LW13SSIT The Orion Research Subsidies have become law.
\*LW14SSIT The Humane Labor Law is now in effect.
\*LW15SSIT The Orion Summit Meeting has begun.
\*LW16SSIT The Homeland Defense Bill has been ratified.
\*LW17SSIT The Forced Labor Reparations Bill has been enacted.
\*LW18SSIT The Anti-Spying Initiative has been adopted by the Senate.
\*LW19SSIT The Weapon Inspections Referendum is now in effect. Weapons inspectors now have access to our Research Facilities.
\*LW20SSIT The Ban on Nuclear Weapons is now in effect.
\*LW21SSIT The Ban on Biological Weapons is now in effect.
\*LW22SSIT The Ban on Chemical Weapons is now in effect.
\*LW23SSIT The Jump Lane Tracking Law is now in effect.
\*LW24SSIT Our Empire is now participating in the Galactic Relief Fund.
\*LW25SSIT Orion Database Standardization has been adopted by our Empire.
\*LW26SSIT
\*LW27SSIT
\*LW28SSIT
\*LW29SSIT

\*LW01ESIT The Senate Peace Accord has expired. (Watch out, your neighbors are building warships!)
\*LW02ESIT The Anti-cloning Initiative has expired.  Reproduction by Cloning is now legal once more.  Population Growth rates are returning to normal.
\*LW03ESIT The Spaceport Taxation law has been revoked.
\*LW04ESIT The Senate Audit has ended.  We are cleared of any involvement with Smuggling or Piracy.
\*LW05ESIT The Senate Research Program has ended in an apparent failure, with little in the way of results to show from it.
\*LW06ESIT The New Orion holiday has been "<Deleted by Rantz>".
\*LW07ESIT The Orion Recycling Initiative has ended.
\*LW08ESIT The Orion Senate Farming Subsidies have ended.
\*LW09ESIT The Orion Senate Mining Subsidies have ended.
\*LW10ESIT Standardized Working Hours are no longer being observed.
\*LW11ESIT The Natural Preservation Initiative has ended.
\*LW12ESIT The Travel and Tourism Initiative has ended.
\*LW13ESIT The Orion Research Subsidies have ended.
\*LW14ESIT The Humane Labor Law is no longer being enforced.
\*LW15ESIT The Orion Summit Meeting has ended in success.
\*LW16ESIT The Homeland Defense Bill has been terminated due to lack of efficiency.
\*LW17ESIT We have met our obligations as required by the Forced Labor Reparations Bill.
\*LW18ESIT The Anti-Spying Initiative has outlived its usefulness.
\*LW19ESIT The Weapon Inspections Referendum has ended.
\*LW20ESIT The Ban on Nuclear Weapons has ended.
\*LW21ESIT The Ban on Biological Weapons has ended.
\*LW22ESIT The Ban on Chemical Weapons has ended.
\*LW23ESIT The Jump Lane Tracking Law has ended.
\*LW24ESIT The Galactic Relief Fund has been disbanded due to accounting irregularities. The leader Cha Hode' is currently being investigated for his role in this.
\*LW25ESIT Orion Database Standardization is no longer followed by our Empire.
\*LW26ESIT
\*LW27ESIT
\*LW28ESIT
\*LW29ESIT
