\\Push & Pull Values

\\Push Values...
\*PUSHUNEM Unemployment
\*PUSHTAXS High Taxes
\*PUSHSLSM Small Stick Levy
\*PUSHSLME Medium Stick Levy
\*PUSHSLBI Big Stick Levy
\*PUSHSTAR Starvation
\*PUSHUNRE Unrest
\*PUSHREVO Revolt
\*PUSHCORL Corrupt Leader
\*PUSHINCL Incompetent Leader
\*PUSHHOSE Hostile Environment
\*PUSHPOLL Polluted
\*PUSHDENP Dense Population
\*PUSHOVEP Overpopulation
\*PUSHMADE Manifest Destiny
\*PUSHLOSS Low Social State
\*PUSHGENO Race Genocide
\*PUSHFOMI Forced Migration
\*PUSHDEPO Deportation
\*PUSHENMI Encouraged Migration
\*PUSHREPE Religious Persecution
\*PUSHSLSM Strip Mine Slavery
\*PUSHSLSD Slavery Show Disc
\*PUSHSLPR Rel. Per. Slavery
\*PUSHOPPR Oppressometer

\\Pull Values...
\*PULLPDIS Planet Distance
\*PULLHABG Green Hab. Zone
\*PULLHABY Yellow Hab. Zone
\*PULLHABR Red Hab. Zone
\*PULLPSSP Same Species
\*PULLPSRA Same Race
\*PULLPSRE Same Religion
\*PULLNOPP No Population
\*PULLMXPP Max. Population
\*PULLSUBS Subsidies
\*PULLGHER Race Ghettoized
\*PULLGHEE Ethos Ghettoized
\*PULLLOIM Local Immigration
\*PULLNOAR No Available Region
\*PULLSPEC Planet Special
\*PULLCSRA Civ. Same Race
\*PULLCSSP Civ. Same Species
\*PULLCBIA Casus Belli Above
\*PULLCBIB Casus Belli Below
\*PULLSOSA Social State Above
\*PULLSOSB Social State Below
\*PULLGENR Race Genocide
\*PULLRFOM Race Forced Migration
\*PULLRGRD Race Gradual Deport
\*PULLRENM Race Encouraged Migration
\*PULLRIND Race Indifference
\*PULLRTOL Race Tolerance
\*PULLRENI Race Encouraged Immigration
\*PULLREAC Race Easy Citizen
\*PULLREQU Race Equality
\*PULLREPE Religion Persecuted
\*PULLRETD Religion Tolerated
\*PULLREWE Religion Welcomed
\*PULLRETC Religion Tolerance
\*PULLREFR Religious Freedom