|BLANK|""
|RSInAt01|"Let's get them!"
|RSInAt02|"Enemy on the move, sir!"
|RSInAt03|"Launch the attack!"
|RSInAt04|"We've engaged the enemy!"
|RSInAt05|"Attack!"
|RSInAt06|"Hit them hard, troops!"
|RSInDe01|"Incoming!"
|RSInDe02|"They're hitting us, sir!"
|RSInDe03|"We're under fire!"
|RSInDe04|"Enemy fire reported!"
|RSInDe05|"Enemy advance detected!"
|RSInDe06|"The enemy's attacking, sir!"
|RSWLDW01|"The battle's ours!"
|RSWLDW02|"We've won this fight, sir."
|RSWLDW03|"Secure the area!"
|RSWLDW04|"We beat them this time, general."
|RSWLDW05|"The enemy's falling back, sir!"
|RSWLDW06|"Victory is ours!"
|RSWLDL01|"We're beaten, commander."
|RSWLDL02|"They got us this time, sir."
|RSWLDL03|"Fall back!"
|RSWLDL04|"Sound the retreat!"
|RSWLDL05|"We've lost this battle, sir."
|RSWLDL06|"They were too much for us, sir."
|RSWLDD01|"A lot of work for no change, sir."
|RSWLDD02|"Nothing gained or lost this time."
|RSWLDD03|"Looks like a draw, general."
|RSWLDD04|"The battle was indecisive, sir."
|RSWLDD05|"Sir, we fought them to a draw."
|RSWLDD06|"Too much fighting for no result, general."
|RSUINFW1|"Our ground troops are dishing out the punishment, sir!"
|RSUMARW1|"They didn't count on having to fight our marines, sir!"
|RSUMOBW1|"The mobile units are too much for them to handle, commander."
|RSUARMW1|"The armored divisions are entering the field now, sir."
|RSUBARW1|"The Battleoids are pounding them hard, sir."
|RSUPSYW1|"We have successfully shattered the enemy's morale, sir."
|RSUCOMW1|"The commandos are in position now, general."
|RSUHACW1|"Their computer security is virtually nonexistent."
|RSUCMCW1|"We're proving the value of good command, sir!"
|RSUMAGW1|"That extra ammunition is just what we needed, commander!"
|RSUINFW2|"Our ground forces are assuming positions."
|RSUMARW2|"The marines are landing, general!"
|RSUMOBW2|"The mobile infantry is assuming positions now, sir."
|RSUARMW2|"Our armor is too tough for them, commander."
|RSUBATW2|"They can't stand up to our Battleoids, commander!"
|RSUPSYW2|"The enemy's morale is our plaything."
|RSUCOMW2|"Our commandos are picking them apart, commander!"
|RSUHACW2|"Look at your screen, commander; I think you'll want to see this."
|RSUCMCW2|"The enemies special units are no match for us, sir."
|RSUMAGW2|"Logistics clearly favor us in this campaign, general."
|RSUINFW3|"You can count on the infantry to get you that territory, sir."
|RSUMARW3|"Our marines are more than a match for them, sir."
|RSUMOBW3|"The mobile infantry is advancing rapidly on the enemy."
|ESUARMW3|"They don't even slow our armor, general."
|RSUBATW3|"The Battleoids are deciding things in our favor, general."
|RSUPSYW3|"Their will to fight crumbles before our onslaught, sir."
|RSUCOMW3|"The commandos are as silent but deadly as ever, general."
|RSUHACW3|"Our hackers have scrambled their computers, sir!"
|RSUCMCW3|"Our Command Center is saving the day, general."
|RSUMAGW3|"We're going to run out of enemy long before we run out of ammo, general."
|RSUINFl1|"Our infantry can't hold, sir."
|RSUMARl1|"Our marines can't take the punishment, commander."
|RSUMOBL1|"They caught the mobile infantry out in the open, commander. It isn't pretty."
|RSUARML1|"They are punching through our armor like it's paper!"
|RSUBATL1|"Our Battleoids just aren't enough, sir."
|RSUPSYL1|"The enemy is proving to be most resistant to our PsyOps, commander."
|RSUCOML1|"Our commandos' positions are being overrun, general."
|RSUHACL1|"Our hackers aren't up to the challenge of their security, sir."
|RSUCMCL1|"Command Center reports heavy fire, general!"
|RSUMAGL1|"Sir, we MUST have more supplies!"
|RSUINFL2|"The grunts just can't stop the enemy, general."
|RSUMARL2|"The marines are reporting heavy fire, sir!"
|RSUMOBL2|"Mobile infantry needs to be pulled back before it's too late, commander."
|RSUARML2|"Sir, armor is under heavy attack!"
|RSUBATL2|"They're turning our Battleoids into scrap metal, general!"
|RSUPSYL2|"Our PsyOps are ineffective in this battle, sir."
|RSUCOML2|"They must've been expecting commando tricks, sir!"
|RSUHACL2|"We can't crack their counter-measures, sir."
|RSUCMCL2|"The command center is unable to deal with enemy harassment, sir."
|RSUMAGL2|"Sir, without proper supplies victory is impossible."
|RSUINFL3|"The infantry is reporting heavy fire, sir!"
|RSUMARL3|"We have to pull the marines back NOW, general!"
|RSUMOBL3|"This isn't the mobile infantry's battlefield, sir."
|RSUARML3|"Commander, they're shredding our armor!"
|RSUBATL3|"The enemy is tearing apart our Battleoid formations, commander."
|RSUPSYL3|"They are just too tough for our PsyOps, general!"
|RSUCOML3|"The enemy is just too tough for our commandos, general."
|RSUHACL3|"Our hackers are taking it hard, commander."
|RSUCMCL3|"They're breaking through to our Command Center, sir!"
|RSUMAGL3|"We need more than ammunition today, commander!"
|RSSHUMW1|"This battle is worthy of The Book!"
|RSSETHW1|"Our forces are entwined. We shall withstand this storm."
|RSSGEOW1|"Our forces work in tono, sir!"
|RSSCYBW1|"Corruption to their spawn!"
|RSSICHW1|"Their forces are as weak as land walkers ."
|RSSHARW1|"We shall tap their bodies this night."
|RSSINSW1|"We are cleaving the enemy from our presence!"
|RSSSAUW1|"Earth and fire, victory will be ours!"
|RSSMETW1|"Amgine himself could not do better!"
|RSSNONW1|"Our Aurora is strong, commander."
|RSSPROW1|"This battle is a superb meld, sir."
|RSSPLAW1|"We are laying down deep roots toward victory!"
|RSSFUNW1|"We shall grow strong with this victory."
|RSSAVIW1|"We shall have victory this day!"
|RSSGARW1|"Perhaps now they will understand better the waste their haste makes."
|RSSHUMW2|"We are seizing the initiative, general."
|RSSETHW2|"The deeps are taking our enemy."
|RSSGEOW2|"Our battle plan is pure resonnor. The enemy has no chance!"
|RSSCYBW2|"Our forces shine! The enemy cannot withstand us!"
|RSSICHW2|"Our plans are filled with The Fathom, sir."
|RSSHARW2|"Remember to take prisoners. We shall need them later."
|RSSINSW2|"Our Kra'ktar is proving superior!"
|RSSSAUW2|"This victory will be remembered as the beginning of the dawning."
|RSSMETW2|"Victory will be far too simple. Perhaps next time we will face real troops."
|RSSNONW2|"The old ways are indeed the best ways, commander."
|RSSPROW2|"Victory will flow seamlessly, commander."
|RSSPLAW2|"Victory is inevitable! Our troops move swiftly as scramblers!"
|RSSFUNW2|"The enemy will taste nothing but our spores in their defeat."
|RSSAVIW2|"Once more victory will be seized by the bold."
|RSSGARW2|"Our warriors fight with the aggressiveness of muchata."
|RSSHUML1|"Stubbornness does not look sufficient to win the day, sir."
|RSSETHL1|"It is only with saeer that our defeat can be understood."
|RSSGEOL1|"From the beginning our forces were filled with vishana; defeat is inevitable."
|RSSCYBL1|"We are losing! This is encryptable!"
|RSSICHL1|"How can land walkers defeat us?"
|RSSHARL1|"Does this defeat affect my chances of tapping new meat?"
|RSSINSL1|"The cleavers among us are bringing defeat!"
|RSSSAUL1|"Weaklings and amphiats, there can be no other reason for our difficulty!"
|RSSMETL1|"Losing to egglayers? Impossible!"
|RSSNONL1|"Our troops fight like mere solids, general."
|RSSPROL1|"The flow of our troops wanes dangerously, sir."
|RSSPLAL1|"Our troops are as a trailing vine without firm roots. Defeat comes!"
|RSSFUNL1|"We are losing!  We must adapt the enemy's techniques!"
|RSSAVIL1|"This battle is slipping from our talons!"
|RSSGARL1|"Even the Wusita will have trouble if this leads to defeat."
|RSSHUML2|"Our troops fight no better than mere apes, commander."
|RSSETHL2|"Too many members of our army go to the deeps in this battle."
|RSSGEOL2|"The enemy exploits a soor in our battle plan! Defeat shall swiftly follow!"
|RSSCYBL2|"Corruption has struck!  We are being defeated!"
|RSSICHL2|"By the Old One, we are losing!"
|RSSHARL2|"I told you that the stasis farms dulled our sense of the hunt."
|RSSINSL2|"It appears that the enemy knows something of Kra'ktar as well."
|RSSSAUL2|"Only by ignoring all tenets of herpatra are they able to deny us."
|RSSMETL2|"How can you lead us to defeat by egglayers, general ?!"
|RSSNONL2|"We have improperly followed the old ways, sir.  Defeat comes."
|RSSPROL2|"Our troops meld poorly, general."
|RSSPLAL2|"We are being uprooted!"
|RSSFUNL2|"We must create a new spore of battle, commander."
|RSSAVIL2|"We shame ourselves before the Ascendant One!"
|RSSGARL2|"The herd will be greatly weakened by a defeat here."
|RSTMAW01|"Our concentration of force was too much for them to handle."
|RSTVEW01|"We hit them where they weren't expecting us to, sir!"
|RSTPAW01|"We have caught them within our multipronged assault."
|RSTSWW01|"We've punched through to their rear, general!"
|RSTPRW01|"Our recent probe of the enemy's strength has gained us a valuable advantage."
|RSTHAW01|"Our harassment strikes are having the desired effect, general."
|RSTECW01|"Our attacking waves were just too much for them, general."
|RSTATW01|"The rate of attrition clearly favors our side."
|RSTFLW01|"We've outflanked them, general!  Now for the kill!"
|RSTMNW01|"The enemy was unable to keep pace with our maneuvers, general."
|RSTLRW01|"We grabbed some key points easily, general."
|RSTFNW01|"The enemy didn't realize it was a feint until way too late, sir."
|RSTRSW01|"Congratulations, commander, our troops pulled off the ruse brilliantly."
|RSTSUW01|"We caught them by complete surprise, sir!"
|RSTTRW01|"They have fallen into our trap!"
|RSTDVW01|"The enemy is successfully divided. Now comes the conquest."
|RSTSLW01|"Our line defense held off the enemy, sir!"
|RSTSDW01|"Our depth of defense blunted their worthless attack, sir."
|RSTFRW01|"They were unable to break through our fortifications."
|RSTRTW01|"We have successfully fallen back, general."
|RSTFWW01|"Commander, I am sure we will hold them here."
|RSTAMW01|"The enemy never suspected that it was an ambush until it was too late."
|RSTMAW02|"They were unable to withstand our massed assault, commander."
|RSTVEW02|"We've got the angle on them now, sir."
|RSTPAW02|"We've got their big guns pinned, sir; we'll take them all out now."
|RSTSWW02|"We've cut them off from their support, sir!"
|RSTPRW02|"We've found their weak points; we'll pound them now, sir."
|RSTHAW02|"We are successfully wearing the enemy down with our continued harassment."
|RSTECW02|"We pounded them relentlessly, sir."
|RSTATW02|"We've caused them enough pain to break them."
|RSTFLW02|"Success! We're hitting them in the flank now!"
|RSTMNW02|"Now we have them right where we want them, sir."
|RSTLRW02|"They let us take too much land for their own good, sir."
|RSTFNW02|"Our feint worked brilliantly, commander."
|RSTRSW02|"The enemy didn't catch on until way too late, general."
|RSTSUW02|"Surprise was total, general. They never saw it coming."
|RSTTRW02|"Fools do indeed rush in."
|RSTDVW02|"We have driven a wedge between the enemy's formations."
|RSTSLW02|"They fell before our line, general."
|RSTSDW02|"They just couldn't push through our deep defenses, general."
|RSTFRW02|"Thanks to these fortifications, the enemy was unable to advance."
|RSTRTW02|"We've managed to retreat in good order, general."
|RSTFWW02|"We blunted their attack with that fighting withdrawal, sir."
|RSTAMW02|"We ambushed the enemy! They're ours now!"
|RSTMAL01|"Our wedge was too tight, and we presented too good a target."
|RSTVEL01|"They were waiting for us to try the envelopment, sir."
|RSTPAL01|"They just wouldn't let us pin them down, sir."
|RSTSWL01|"We were unable to dislodge the enemy with our sweep."
|RSTPRL01|"I fear our probing attack exposed serious weaknesses in our army."
|RSTHAL01|"Our harassment tactics are ineffective, sir."
|RSTECL01|"Wave after wave went to defeat, sir."
|RSTATL01|"We should rethink our policy of attrition warfare, sir."
|RSTFLL01|"The enemy managed to avoid being outflanked sir."
|RSTMNL01|"They were able to keep pace with our maneuvers, general."
|RSTLRL01|"I fear our limited resistance was a bit more limited than we hoped for."
|RSTFNL01|"They didn't buy the feint for even a moment, general."
|RSTRSL01|"They saw through our ruse from the beginning, commander."
|RSTSUL01|"We failed to take them by surprise, sir."
|RSTTRL01|"I don't know how, but they managed to escape our trap."
|RSTDVL01|"We couldn't force a way through the enemy formations, sir."
|RSTSLL01|"Depth of forces might have been a better choice, sir."
|RSTSDL01|"Our defenses are spread out too thin to even slow them down."
|RSTFRL01|"The enemy has bypassed our fortifications, sir."
|RSTRTL01|"Our retreat came dangerously close to a rout, general."
|RSTFWL01|"The fighting withdrawal just wasn't enough, general."
|RSTAML01|"They must have expected an ambush, sir."
|RSTMAL02|"They blunted our wedge, and we were unable to advance, sir."
|RSTVEL02|"It was almost as if they knew where we'd be headed, general."
|RSTPAL02|"We just couldn't exploit their weaknesses effectively, general."
|RSTSWL02|"We swept, they countered, sir."
|RSTPRL02|"They smashed our probes pretty badly, sir."
|RSTHAL02|"They're too tough for us to harass, general!"
|RSTECL02|"The enemy was tireless in holding us off, general."
|RSTATL02|"If this rate of attrition continues, general, it'll be our side that runs out of troops first."
|RSTFLL02|"They were too smart to be outflanked, sir."
|RSTMNL02|"They figured out our maneuvers before we could, sir."
|RSTLRL02|"Sadly, our limited resistance met with unlimited aggression."
|RSTFNL02|"They didn't react to the feint, sir."
|RSTRSL02|"We just didn't sell the ruse effectively, commander."
|RSTSUL02|"Looks like the surprise was on us, general."
|RSTTRL02|"They anticipated our trap, sir; things look grim."
|RSTDVL02|"Our troops advanced too slowly to divide the enemy, general."
|RSTSLL02|"Our line was defeated by the enemy's subtlety, sir."
|RSTSDL02|"Had our defenses been concentrated, we would have won."
|RSTFRL02|"Our fortifications didn't even slow them down, general."
|RSTRTL02|"The enemy hit us hard during our retreat, general."
|RSTFWL02|"We needed more fighting, and less withdrawal, sir."
|RSTAML02|"They got out of our ambush.  How?  HOW?"
|RSOMAW01|"There were just too many of them at the point of attack, general."
|RSOVEW01|"Sir, they're all around us!"
|RSOPAW01|"They caught us in a multipronged attack, commander."
|RSOSWW01|"They've cut the rear area off from the troops, sir!"
|RSOPRW01|"We mistook their probe for their main attack, sir."
|RSOHAW01|"These harassment strikes are wearing down our troops, general."
|RSOECW01|"Their endless waves are exhausting our troops, sir!"
|RSOATW01|"I am not certain how much longer we can sustain this rate of attrition."
|RSOFLW01|"Sir, the enemy has outflanked us!"
|RSOMNW01|"We've been badly outmaneuvered, commander."
|RSOLRW01|"They're grabbing too much key land, sir!"
|RSOFNW01|"They tricked us into countering the wrong way, sir."
|RSORSW01|"We were fooled by the enemy, sir."
|RSOSUW01|"We have been taken by complete surprise, commander."
|RSOTRW01|"Sir, the enemy has managed to entrap us!"
|RSODVW01|"Sir, the enemy has split our formations apart."
|RSOSLW01|"Their single line was just too strong a defense, sir."
|RSOSDW01|"They're spread too thinly for us to defeat more than a handful of them."
|RSOFRW01|"Their fortifications are just too strong, general."
|RSORTW01|"The enemy is falling back in good order, general."
|RSOFWW01|"They're pulling back, general, but they're still showing some fight."
|RSOAMW01|"A trick, general! We've been ambushed!"
|RSOMAL01|"They made such a nice target, sitting together like that."
|RSOVEL01|"We picked them right out of the sky, sir."
|RSOPAL01|"Their prongs weren't sharp enough to pierce our defenses, sir."
|RSOSWL01|"We kept them from reaching the rear, general."
|RSOPRL01|"They looked for weaknesses, and found their own."
|RSOHAL01|"They'll have to do more than just harass us, sir."
|RSOECL01|"We are defeating their echelon formation section by section."
|RSOATL01|"Don't they realize that continued attrition works in our favor?"
|RSOFLL01|"It was touchy for a while there, general, but our flank is secure."
|RSOMNL01|"Did they think they could outmaneuver us?"
|RSOLRL01|"If they want this area, they'll have to fight for it!"
|RSOFNL01|"Was it just me or was that feint way too obvious to succeed?"
|RSORSL01|"Looks like someone got too clever for his own good!"
|RSOSUL01|"Seems they were the ones who got the surprise, general."
|RSOTRL01|"The fools! We can spot their traps miles away!"
|RSODVL01|"As if we would allow ourselves to be divided so easily!"
|RSOSLL01|"We punched through that single line; it's all over, sir."
|RSOSDL01|"Their defenses are spread too thinly to stop us now."
|RSOFRL01|"They had the nerve to call those fortifications?"
|RSORTL01|"We've got 'em on the run now sir!"
|RSOFWL01|"I believe the enemy withdrew a bit further than he expected to."
|RSOAML01|"We sniffed out that ambush, sir, and made them sorry they tried it."
|RSECHL01|"We definitely need more gunnery practice, commander"
|RSECDL01|"The enemy seems to be impervious to our weapons."
|RSEGOL01|"There are too many of the enemy for us to even begin to count."
|RSEONL01|"Sir, fighting at these odds is difficult."
|RSEMBL01|"When the army stops running away, general, I will relay your new orders to them."
|RSEGTL01|"We've gained a lot of land, sir."
|RSECCL01|"We have gained valuable time, my liege."
|RSESLL01|"The fighting has been endless, sir, and still no one is victorious."
|RSESUL01|"I have sent your request of surrender to the enemy, sir."
|RSEAWL01|"The planet is lost to us for now, general, but we will return to reclaim it."
|RSEDWL01|"Congratulations, commander! The enemy is in complete retreat"
|RSEHEL01|"The grunts are complaining about the conditions, sir. They don't like it one bit."
|RSEBGL01|"This terrain will work to our advantage, sir."
|RSECHL02|"The enemy is evading practically everything we fire at him, sir."
|RSECDL02|"If we are going to have a chance, sir, we need more powerful arms."
|RSEGOL02|"There are too many of them. We NEED reinforcements, commander."
|RSEONL02|"We are outnumbered, commander!"
|RSEMBL02|"Our troops are routing, sir. We're in trouble!"
|RSEGTL02|"General, our troops report capturing a strategic position!"
|RSECCL02|"We've stalled them a little longer, commander."
|RSESLL02|"Our forces are equal, general. No one can win this war."
|RSESUL02|"I've ordered the army to stand down. It's been an honor serving with you, sir."
|RSEAWL02|"We must lift off now, general, while we still have a chance to escape."
|RSEDWL02|"I believe the enemy will think twice about attacking us again, sir."
|RSEHEL02|"We shouldn't have come here sir. We don't belong in this environment."
|RSEBGL02|"This is the perfect ground for our troops to fight in."
|RSECHL03|"We can't seem to hit the enemy no matter how hard we try."
|RSECDL03|"Something seems to be wrong with our weapons today, general."
|RSEGOL03|"They're everywhere! They've got too many troops, sir!"
|RSEONL03|"Sir, we could use reinforcements to even things up a bit."
|RSEMBL03|"Disaster! The army's morale is broken."
|RSEGTL03|"Commander, our forces have advanced deeper into enemy territory."
|RSECCL03|"We stand resilient. The enemy shall not capture us alive."
|RSESLL03|"We have reached a deadlock, commander."
|RSESUL03|"Are you sure about the surrender order, general? I think our troops still have some fight in them."
|RSEAWL03|"HQ will not like hearing about our defeat, sir."
|RSEDWL03|"The rumor has been confirmed. All remaining enemy units on planet are lifting off from planet, general."
|RSEHEL03|"The environment is taking a toll on morale, general. The soldiers can't take it for long."
|RSEBGL03|"We clearly have the advantage in this environment."
|RSECHO01|"It doesn't seem like they can hit us, sir."
|RSECDO01|"They call that a weapon?"
|RSEGOO01|"The odds clearly favor us, general"
|RSEONO01|"We've got numbers on our side, general."
|RSEMBO01|"The enemy's fleeing, sir!"
|RSEGTO01|"We've lost some more real estate to the enemy, general."
|RSECCO01|"They can't stall us indefinitely, commander."
|RSESLO01|"It's no use, commander; the forces are too evenly matched."
|RSESUO01|"Congratulations, general, the enemy has just surrendered."
|RSEAWO01|"Congratulations, general. I am sure our leader will reward you for your efforts here."
|RSEDWO01|"The army has fallen back, commander. We cannot take this planet."
|RSEHEO01|"Our reports show severe morale damage to the enemy, sir! They don't like it here!"
|RSEBGO01|"This terrain clearly favors the enemy."
|RSECHO02|"Thankfully, the enemy doesn't seem to believe in target practice."
|RSECDO02|"Our armor is practically impervious to their weapons."
|RSEGOO02|"We have far more troops than the enemy, sir."
|RSEONO02|"We have the enemy outnumbered."
|RSEMBO02|"Their morale is shattered, general. All that remains is to land the final blow."
|RSEGTO02|"How much longer can we afford to surrender territory, commander?"
|RSECCO02|"They cannot continue to hold out forever, general."
|RSESLO02|"Stalemate, general. I don't know how we'll break the deadlock."
|RSESUO02|"Do you wish to accept the enemy's surrender, general?"
|RSEAWO02|"This world is ours now!"
|RSEDWO02|"This colony is too well defended. We must retreat, sir."
|RSEHEO02|"The enemy can't stand the environment, can he? We shall make him suffer yet."
|RSEBGO02|"I hate fighting in this type of terrain, general."
|RSECHO03|"It takes little skill to evade those shots, general."
|RSECDO03|"Those heavy investments in armor and shield tech are paying off."
|RSEGOO03|"Our numbers are overwhelming!"
|RSEONO03|"We have them outgunned...now it's time to pull the trigger."
|RSEMBO03|"Their formations are breaking, sir!"
|RSEGTO03|"The enemy has taken yet more ground from us, general."
|RSECCO03|"Just a momentary pause, general. Victory will be ours soon enough."
|RSESLO03|"This continued stalemate favors no one, general."
|RSESUO03|"I am honored to announce that the enemy has formally surrendered."
|RSEAWO03|"I am sure our people will be happy on this world commander."
|RSEDWO03|"The planet is still theirs, sir.  We just couldn't capture it."
|RSEHEO03|"Their lazy grunts can't take a little hardship. We'll take advantage of them yet."
|RSEBGO03|"It's going to get bloody if we have to fight on this terrain for long."
