\\UI strings - leave here at the top
\*SITRGCYC GALACTIC CYCLE
\*SITRGTRN GAME TURN
\*SITRFLTR FILTERS:
\*SITRFLT1 Green Items
\*SITRFLT2 Yellow Items
\*SITRFLT3 Espionage
\*SITRFLT4 Military Const. 
\*SITRFLT5 Red Items
\*SITRFLT6 Tech Breakthroughs
\*SITRFLT7 Construction
\*SITRFLT8 Built Task Forces
\*SITRFLT9 Migration

\\SitrepReporter formats
\*SITRF001 Space combat occurred between %race1% and %race2%. %value1% now owns %subject%.
\*SITRF002 Space combat occurred between %race1% and %race2%. %value1% now owns %subject%.
\*SITRF003 Space combat occurred between %race1% and %race2%. %value1% now owns %subject%.
\*SITRF004 %race1% have made a research breakthrough in the field of %subject%.
\*SITRF005 %race1% have made a research breakthrough in the field of %subject%.
\*SITRF006 %race1% have made a research breakthrough in the field of %subject%.
\*SITRF007 Good news! %Value1% is now ready to enter the prototype phase.  We will send updates on our progress.
\*SITRF008 Our scientists report Level %Value2% of %Value1% has been completed.
\*SITRF009 %Value1% is now complete and ready to be used.
\*SITRF010 %Value1% has reached completion. In addition, there were some unexpected new discoveries which have given us a positive overrun.
\*SITRF011 Protests against %Value1% have required us to increase security, so it will take another %Value2% turns to complete the project.
\*SITRF014 Primary exploration of %Value1% has been completed.
\*SITRF015 Primary exploration of %Value1% has been completed.  Exciting news...%Value2% was discovered.
\*SITRF016 Exploration of %Value1% has been completed.
\*SITRF017 Exploration of %Value1% has been completed.  During the exploration %Value2% was discovered.
\*SITRF018 Exploration of %Value1% is now complete.
\*SITRF019 We have started a research project on %Value1%.
\*SITRF020 The technology project %Value1% has been cancelled.
\*SITRF021 The technology project %Value1% is now visible.
\*SITRF022 The project %Value1% has become available for research.
\*SITRF023 Your forces have encountered forces belonging to the %Value1% civilization at %Value2%.
\*SITRCOL1 A colony ship belonging to your Empire has landed at %Value1%.
\*SITRCOL2 A colony task force belonging to your Empire has been formed and assigned to land on %Value1%.
\*SITROUT2 An Outpost task force belonging to your Empire has been assigned to land on %Value1%.
\*SITRCOL3 A colony task force belonging to your Empire was unable to find a place to land at %Value1%. The task force has being disbanded and its ships sent to the reserves.
\*SITTEST1 %Value1% civilization has been attacked by our spies.
\*SITTEST2 %Value2% has been destroyed on planet %Value1%.
\*SITRF025 Construction of %Value2% has been completed on planet %Value1%.
\*ANTARA01 The Antaran expedition has discovered a destination: Archaeological Investigation will begin next turn.
\*ANTARA02 The Antaran expedition has lost a ship trying to discover a destination.
\*ANTARA03 The Antaran expedition has made a partial archeological discovery.
\*ANTARA04 The Antaran expedition has discovered an Antaran "X": Inbound voyage will begin next turn.
\*ANTARA05 The Antaran expedition has lost a ship during its archeological investigation.
\*ANTARA06 The Antaran expedition has transmitted information about an Antaran "X": Institutionalization of this discovery can now begin.
\*ANTARA07 The Antaran expedition has returned to the Orion Sector: Expedition ships have been placed in the Imperial Reserves.
\*ANTARA08 The Antaran expedition has lost a ship during the inbound voyage.
\*ANTARA09 The Antaran expedition has ended in failure: All expedition ships have been lost.
\*SENELRP1 The Orion Senate convenes to elect a new %Value1%.
\*SPDSC01 %Value2% special has been discovered on planet %Value1%.
\*SPDSC12 While exploring a new system the %Value1% technology has been discovered.
\*SPDSC13 A leader has been discovered while exploring a new system.

\*DIPLOMAC Diplomacy
\*DIPLO001 You have pending <H>#<Diplomacy>#Diplomacy<H> messages.
\*DIPLO002 There are <H>#<Diplomacy>#Diplomacy<H> messages waiting for your response.
\*DIPLO003 Sir, we've been contacted by other Empires. You can respond through the <H>#<Diplomacy>#Diplomacy<H> Screen.
\*DIPLO004 The %Value2% Empire has accepted your Diplomatic Offer.
\*DIPLO005 We've received word from the %Value2% Empire that they have accepted our offer.
\*DIPLO006 Our diplomats have returned from the %Value2% Empire. They have accepted our offer.
\*DIPLO007 Word has returned. The %Value2% Empire has refused our offer.
\*DIPLO008 The %Value2% Empire has responded. I'm afraid they've turned down our offer.
\*DIPLO009 Our offer has been rejected by the %Value2% Empire.
\*DIPLO010 The %Value2% Empire has responded to our message with its own counter offer.
\*DIPLO011 Sir, one of the messages pending from the %Value2% Empire is a counter offer.
\*DIPLO012 Your diplomats are awaiting word on a counter offer presented by the %Value2% Empire.
\*DIPLO013 Sir! We've received word that the %Value2% Empire has declared war!
\*DIPLO014 Diplomats have just arrived with news that the %Value2% Empire has declared war on us!
\*DIPLO015 We're at war sir! The %Value2% Empire has declared war on us.
\*DIPLO016 The %Value2% Empire has sent word that they're breaking their treaties with us!
\*DIPLO017 Our diplomats have returned with messages from the %Value2% Empire. They've broken their treaties with us.
\*DIPLO018 Our treaties with the %Value2% Empire have been broken sir.
\*DIPLO019 Sir, our enforced peace with the %Value2% Empire will be expiring in %Value3% turns.
\*DIPLO020 We've received a reminder that our enforced peace with the %Value2% Empire will expire in %Value3% turns.
\*DIPLO021 Reminder: Your enforced peace will be expiring with the %Value2% Empire in %Value3% turns.
\*DIPLO022 Our enforced peace treaty with the %Value2% Empire has expired.
\*DIPLO023 The diplomats have sent word that the enforced peace treaty with the %Value2% Empire has expired.
\*DIPLO024 Sir, we no longer have an enforced peace treaty with the %Value2% Empire.
\*DIPLO025 Sir! The %Value2% Empire has broken their trade agreements with us.
\*DIPLO026 Our trade agreements with the %Value2% Empire have been broken.
\*DIPLO027 Our diplomats have received word that the %Value2% Empire has broken their trade agreements with us.
\*SBATTL01 Sir! Our forces on %Value1% have suffered a terrible defeat defending the planet. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL02 Sir! Our forces on %Value1% have been overwhelmed and have lost the battle. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL03 The battle at %Value1% has been lost and our forces have been destroyed. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL04 Our forces report that they were successful in defending %Value1% from its attackers. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL05 The battle at %Value1% has resulted in a success. Our forces have defended the planet. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL06 Sir, reports confirm that we were able to defend planet %Value1% from its attackers. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL07 Sir! The front line reports a defeat with our attack on planet %Value1%. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL08 Our attacking forces have lost the battle sir. %Value1% still remains out of our control. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL09 Terrible news! Our attacking forces report that they were unable to smash the defenses /p on planet %Value1%. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL10 Sir! Reports from the front line tell that our attacking forces have won against the defending fleet at /p%Value1%. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL11 Our attacking forces have reported success in their assault on planet %Value1%. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL12 Victory! Our forces are reporting a successful campaign against %Value1%. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL13 Sir! Our forces in %Value1% have reported defeat. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL14 Terrible News! The battle in %Value1% has resulted in our defeat. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL15 Our forces report that they have lost the battle in the %Value1% system. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL16 Sir! Our forces report victory in %Value1%. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL17 Reports from the military show a victory in %Value1%. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL18 Sir! The battle in %Value1% has resulted in a victory for our forces. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL19 Sir! The battle in the %Value1% system has resulted in a draw and will continue next turn. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL20 The battle in the %Value1% system is still raging and will continue next turn. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL21 Neither side was able to win the battle in the %Value1% system. The battle will continue next turn unless we withdraw our forces. Allied Casualties: %Value2% percent.
\*SBATTL22 Sir! We encountered forces in the %Value1% system, but neither side engaged in battle.
\*SBATTL23 Sir! There was an opposition force in the %Value1% system, however no combat occurred.
\*SBATTL24 Reports from the front tell us we met resistance in the %Value1% system, however no fight took place.
\*COLONY01 Migration has led to our control of planet %Value1%.
\*COLONY02 Pioneers from our Empire have struck out and created a new colony. %Value1% is now under our control.
\*COLONY03 The planet %Value1% has been colonized by migrants from our Empire.
\*UNREST01 The planet %Value1% has reported some disturbing news. There is minor unrest among the populace.
\*UNREST02 Several reports indicate that citizens on %Value1% are unhappy and have caused the planet to go into minor unrest.
\*UNREST03 A case of minor unrest has erupted on %Value1% and is lowering production slightly on that planet.
\*UNREST04 %Value1% is reporting that some of its citizens are taking their anger to the streets due to unrest. No damage is being reported but production is down.
\*UNREST05 Production on %Value1% has dropped due to unrest on the planet.
\*UNREST06 The planet %Value1% is currently experiencing unrest. Production values on the planet have been reduced due to people not at their jobs.
\*UNREST07 The planet %Value1% is experiencing major unrest in some areas. Production has been adversely affected.
\*UNREST08 Sir! We need to deal with the unrest on the planet %Value1%. If we don't, revolt is sure to follow!
\*UNREST09 The unrest on planet %Value1% is getting bad. Production is severely reduced; there is talk of revolt.
\*REVOLT01 The planet %Value1% is revolting! People have taken to the streets there and are destroying buildings in their wake.
\*REVOLT02 Sir! The citizens on planet %Value1% are revolting against its government. Buildings are being destroyed and the military is ineffective.
\*REVOLT03 A revolt is occurring on the planet %Value1%. If things continue as they are we'll lose control of the planet.
\*REVOLT04 Sir! The planet %Value1% has left our Empire due to a planet-wide revolt.
\*REVOLT05 The planet %Value1% has left our Empire! The revolt became too much for our military to handle and we've lost control.
\*REVOLT06 The revolt on planet %Value1% was too much for us to contain. The planet has broken away from our Empire.
\*ENTLD001 The highly regarded %Value1% has decided to join us as a leader.
\*ENTLD002 Having heard tales of your Empire's success, %Value1% has offered to help lead our government.
\*ENTLD003 %Value1% has offered to assist in the governing of our Empire.

\*REVOL001 The planet %Value1% is revolting! People have taken to the streets there and are destroying buildings in their wake. Buildings Destroyed: %Value2%
\*REVOL002 Sir! The citizens on planet %Value1% are revolting against its government. Buildings are being destroyed and the military is ineffective. Buildings Destroyed : %Value2%
\*REVOL003 A revolt is occurring on the planet %Value1%. If things continue as they are we'll lose control of the planet. Buildings Destroyed: %Value2%
\*NEWCOL01 A new planet has been colonized. %Value1% is now ready for your instructions.
\*NEWCOL02 The colony %Value1% has been established.
\*NEWCOL03 A new colony named %Value1% has been created.
\*MIGRAT01 Migration has resulted in new people arriving on %Value1%. %Value2% people have relocated there.
\*MIGRAT02 New colonists are arriving daily on %Value1%. An additional %Value2% people have arrived.
\*MIGRAT03 %Value2% people have arrived on the planet %Value1% this past turn.
\*LOSTPL01 The planet %Value1% is no longer within our control. The population has dropped too far for us to keep an adequate government there.
\*LOSTPL02 Sir, we've lost the planet %Value1% due to the population falling too low.
\*LOSTPL03 The population on planet %Value1% has been dropping steady. As a result, we've lost control of that planet.
\*BILLPR01 A new bill %Value1% has been proposed in the Orion Senate and is awaiting your response.
\*BILLPR02 The Orion Senate has had a new bill %Value1% proposed and is awaiting your attention.
\*BILLPR03 We've received word that a new bill %Value1% has been proposed in the Orion Senate and is awaiting your attention.
\*NEWGRF01 A new ground force has been created on the planet %Value1%.
\*NEWGRF02 The planet %Value1% has established a new ground force there for defense.
\*NEWGRF03 A new ground force has been established on the planet %Value1%.
\*NEWTAF01 A new task force has been formed in the %Value1% system.
\*NEWTAF02 Sir, System %Value1% has established a new task force.
\*NEWTAF03 The new task force we've requested has been established in the %Value1% system.
\*NEWSPY01 The new spy %Value1% is available for insertion.
\*NEWSPY02 We've completed training of %Value1%. The new spy is ready for work.
\*NEWSPY03 A new spy %Value1% is ready for an assignment.
\*SPY01 Our spy %Value1% has retired from service.
\*SPY02 Our spy %Value1% is no longer available to us.
\*SPY03 %Value1% is retiring from service to the Empire.
\*SPY04 The %Value2% Empire has killed all of their imprisoned spies. Our spy %Value1% was one of them.
\*SPY05 Our spy %Value1% was killed when the %Value2% Empire killed all of their imprisoned spies.
\*SPY06 The spy %Value1% has been killed. The %Value2% Empire slaughtered all of the spies they had captured.
\*SPY07 Our spy %Value1% was captured. Before being questioned, he committed suicide to protect our secrets.
\*SPY08 %Value1% has committed suicide. His attempt in the %Value2% were unsuccessful and reports show he was about to be captured.
\*SPY09 Rather than being captured our spy %Value1% has committed suicide.
\*SPY10 Our spy %Value1% has been killed trying to enter the %Value2% Empire.
\*SPY11 While entering the %Value2% Empire our spy %Value1% was killed.
\*SPY12 While trying to evade capture our spy %Value1% was killed.
\*SPY13 Our spy %Value1% couldn't escape from the %Value2% prisons. Rather than being imprisoned he committed suicide instead.
\*SPY14 Our spy %Value1% has committed suicide while trying to escape from %Value2% prisons.
\*SPY15 %Value1% has committed suicide. He was trying to escape from the %Value2% Gulag but was unable to.
\*SPY16 Our spy %Value1% was shot while trying to escape from prison.
\*SPY17 Our spy %Value1% was killed trying to escape from the %Value2% "questioning chambers".
\*SPY18 Our spy %Value1% was slain while attempting to escape through the city streets.
\*SPY19 During his mission, our spy %Value1% was slain by the %Value2%.
\*SPY20 During questioning our spy %Value1% was killed by the %Value2%.
\*SPY21 Our spy %Value1% has been killed. He was being questioned by the %Value2% at the time.
\*SPY22 Our spy %Value1% has been captured.
\*SPY23 %Value1% has been "detained for questioning" while trying to enter the %Value2% Empire.
\*SPY24 While crossing the %Value2% borders our spy %Value1% was captured.
\*SPY25 Our spy %Value1% has been imprisoned for espionage. He's being questioned now.
\*SPY26 One of our spies has been captured and is being questioned. We don't believe %Value1% will talk.
\*SPY27 While crossing the %Value2% borders, our spy %Value1% was captured and is currently being questioned.
\*SPY28 Our spy %Value1% has escaped the %Value2% prisons!
\*SPY29 One of our spies has escaped from the %Value2% prisons. %Value1% is being given a heroes welcome.
\*SPY30 Apparently security in the %Value2% Empire is lax. Our spy %Value1% has escaped confinement.
\*SPY31 %Value1% has escaped capture by sneaking across the %Value2% borders.
\*SPY32 Our spy %Value1% has barely evaded capture while sneaking into the %Value2% Empire.
\*SPY33 Our spy %Value1% has returned. He barely escaped capture but was unable to accomplish the mission.
\*SPY34 After being questioned our spy %Value1% was released. He claims to have revealed nothing.
\*SPY35 Our spy %Value1% has been released from imprisonment.
\*SPY36 Much to our surprise, %Value1% has been released. The %Value2% detained him for espionage but was unable to prove anything.
\*SPY37 Our spy %Value1% was unable to cross the border into the %Value2% Empire.
\*SPY38 The %Value2% borders were too well protected. %Value1% was unable to sneak in.
\*SPY39 %Value1% was repelled at the %Value2% borders. He was unable to complete his mission.
\*SPY40 %Value1% has been unable to complete his mission. He barely avoided capture.
\*SPY41 %Value1% was unable to complete his espionage mission. The guards noticed him before he neared his target.
\*SPY42 %Value2% security was far too tight for %Value1% to complete his mission.
\*SPY43 Our spy %Value1% is unable to cross the border back into our territory. He narrowly escaped capture.
\*SPY44 Our spy %Value1% is unable to cross the border back into our space. Security is too tight.
\*SPY45 The borders are sealed too tight for %Value1%. He has become stuck in %Value2% territory.
\*SPY46 The espionage mission assigned to %Value1% has failed.
\*SPY47 %Value1% was unable to complete his spy mission against the %Value2% Empire.
\*SPY48 The mission assigned to %Value1% has failed. Our Spymaster is extremely disappointed.
\*SPY49 %Value1% was unable to infiltrate the %Value2% borders.
\*SPY50 The espionage mission assigned to %Value1% has been delayed. He was able to get past the %Value2% borders but unable to make contact with the target.
\*SPY51 The mission assigned to %Value1% has been delayed. He was unable to get into %Value2% territory.
\*SPY52 %Value1% has failed to cross the border back into our Empire.
\*SPY53 Due to heightened security, %Value1% had to cease their attempt to enter back into our borders.
\*SPY54 %Value1% is still trying to find a way back into our Empire. The border security is looking closely for spies.
\*SPY55 %Value1% has successfully been inserted into %Value2% territory. A new ID has been given to assist in their mission.
\*SPY56 We have successfully inserted the spy %Value1% into the %Value2% borders.
\*SPY57 The spy %Value1% has been dropped safely into %Value2% territory. The mission will begin shortly.
\*SPY58 We have successfully extracted the spy %Value1% from the %Value2% Empire.
\*SPY59 We have successfully extracted the spy %Value1% from deep within %Value2% territory.
\*SPY60 Our spy %Value1% was been successfully extracted from the %Value2% borders.
\*SPY61 Our interrogators have killed one of our imprisoned spies. The offending spy was a member of the %Value1% Empire.
\*SPY62 A spy sent by the %Value1% Empire has been killed in our prisons.
\*SPY63 We've killed a number of our imprisoned spies. A spy sent by the %Value1% Empire was among them.
\*SPY64 An enemy spy has committed suicide while trying to evade our capture. They preferred to death over capture.
\*SPY65 A spy has committed suicide after being captured. The operative preferred to die rather than divulge secrets.
\*SPY66 A spy has committed suicide. Their capture was imminent.
\*SPY67 Our operatives killed a %Value1% spy while attempting to cross our borders.
\*SPY68 A %Value1% spy was killed while trying to enter our borders.
\*SPY69 Our operatives have killed a spy belonging the %Value1% Empire while trying to enter our borders.
\*SPY70 One of our operatives has killed a spy. Its affiliation was unknown.
\*SPY71 A spy belonging to an unknown Empire has been killed. Its was killed before we could discover who sent it.
\*SPY72 Our security forces have killed a spy belonging. Its employer couldn't be ascertained.
\*SPY73 A spy in our prisons has been killed during interrogation. We've notified the %Value1% Empire of their loss.
\*SPY74 Our interrogators have killed one of the captured spies during interrogation. We've sent word to the %Value1% Empire of their loss.
\*SPY75 During interrogation one of the captured spies was "accidentally" killed. The %Value1% Empire has been notified of their loss.
\*SPY76 A spy attempting to enter our territory has escaped capture from our operatives. We believe they were sent by the %Value1% Empire.
\*SPY77 A spy has evaded our operatives and escaped capture.
\*SPY78 Our operatives report that a spy belonging to the %Value1% Empire has entered our territory. They were unable to apprehend the infiltrator.
\*SPY79 Several spies have been captured, and moved to our interrogation block.
\*SPY80 A spy has escaped our detention block! We believe they are returning to the %Value1% Empire.
\*SPY81 A spy has recently escaped from prison! He managed to slip away before we could discover what empire sent him.
\*SPY82 A spy has somehow managed to escape from our highest security prison. He must be tracked down!
\*SPY83 A spy attempting to enter our territory has been captured. We've learned they were sent by the %Value1% Empire.
\*SPY84 A spy belonging to the %Value1% Empire has been captured trying to infiltrate our territory.
\*SPY85 A spy belonging to the %Value1% Empire has been captured and is being interrogated.
\*SPY86 A spy  managed to slip past security and escape from his detention cell. Fortunately, he could not evade our police units and committed suicide.
\*SPY87 A spy has committed suicide rather than face recapture.
\*SPY88 Our security forces tracked down an escaped spy. He committed suicide at the thought of returning to our interrogation chamber.
\*SPY89 We have transported several enemy agents to our interrogation chambers. We doubt that they will remain silent for long.
\*SPY90 Several prisoners suspected of espionage have been transported to our lowest detention blocks. Even the strongest will surely crack under our interrogation.

\*EmpireKilled The %Value1% empire has been destroyed.
\*EmpireDied The %Value1% empire has been eliminated.
\*LeaderDied Your leader %Value1% has left the service of your empire.
\*EmpBankrupt At our present pace, we will be bankrupt in %Value1% turns.

\*LW01SSIT The Senate Peace Accord has been ratified.
\*LW02SSIT The Anti-cloning Initiative is now in effect.
\*LW03SSIT Spaceport Taxation is now being regulated by the Orion Senate.
\*LW04SSIT Senate Auditors from New Orion have arrived and are examining our accounts in accordance with the Audit.
\*LW05SSIT The Senate Research Program has begun.
\*LW06SSIT A New Orion Holiday has been declared.
\*LW07SSIT The Orion Recycling Initiative has been passed.
\*LW08SSIT The Orion Senate Farming Subsidies have been enacted.
\*LW09SSIT The Orion Senate Mining Subsidies have been enacted.
\*LW10SSIT Standardized Working Hours has been ratified.
\*LW11SSIT The Natural Preservation Initiative has been ratified.
\*LW12SSIT The Travel and Tourism Initiative has been passed.
\*LW13SSIT The Orion Research Subsidies have become law.
\*LW14SSIT The Humane Labor Law is now in effect.
\*LW15SSIT The Orion Summit Meeting has begun.
\*LW16SSIT The Homeland Defense Bill has been ratified.
\*LW17SSIT The Forced Labor Reparations Bill has been enacted.
\*LW18SSIT The Anti-Spying Initiative has been adopted by the Senate.
\*LW19SSIT The Weapon Inspections Referendum is now in effect. Weapons inspectors now have access to our Research Facilities.
\*LW20SSIT The Ban on Nuclear Weapons is now in effect.
\*LW21SSIT The Ban on Biological Weapons is now in effect.
\*LW22SSIT The Ban on Chemical Weapons is now in effect.
\*LW23SSIT The Jump Lane Tracking Law is now in effect.
\*LW24SSIT Our Empire is now participating in the Galactic Relief Fund.
\*LW25SSIT Orion Database Standardization has been adopted by our Empire.
\*LW01ESIT The Senate Peace Accord has expired. (Watch out, your neighbors are building warships!)
\*LW02ESIT The Anti-cloning Initiative has expired.  Reproduction by Cloning is now legal once more.  Population Growth rates are returning to normal.
\*LW03ESIT The Spaceport Taxation law has been revoked.
\*LW04ESIT The Senate Audit has ended.  We are cleared of any involvement with Smuggling or Piracy.
\*LW05ESIT The Senate Research Program has ended in an apparent failure, with little in the way of results to show from it.
\*LW06ESIT The New Orion holiday has been "<Deleted by Rantz>".
\*LW07ESIT The Orion Recycling Initiative has ended.
\*LW08ESIT The Orion Senate Farming Subsidies have ended.
\*LW09ESIT The Orion Senate Mining Subsidies have ended.
\*LW10ESIT Standardized Working Hours are no longer being observed.
\*LW11ESIT The Natural Preservation Initiative has ended.
\*LW12ESIT The Travel and Tourism Initiative has ended.
\*LW13ESIT The Orion Research Subsidies have ended.
\*LW14ESIT The Humane Labor Law is no longer being enforced.
\*LW15ESIT The Orion Summit Meeting has ended in success.
\*LW16ESIT The Homeland Defense Bill has been terminated due to lack of efficiency.
\*LW17ESIT We have met our obligations as required by the Forced Labor Reparations Bill.
\*LW18ESIT The Anti-Spying Initiative has outlived its usefulness.
\*LW19ESIT The Weapon Inspections Referendum has ended.
\*LW20ESIT The Ban on Nuclear Weapons has ended.
\*LW21ESIT The Ban on Biological Weapons has ended.
\*LW22ESIT The Ban on Chemical Weapons has ended.
\*LW23ESIT The Jump Lane Tracking Law has ended.
\*LW24ESIT The Galactic Relief Fund has been disbanded due to accounting irregularities. The leader Cha Hode' is currently being investigated for his role in this.
\*LW25ESIT Orion Database Standardization is no longer followed by our Empire.
\*srDarGrd Your explorations have uncovered the devastated system of %Value1%, once home to the people of the Darlok empire. A Guardian of the New Orions now occupies the system to keep curiosity-seekers at bay.
\*srBulGrd Your Task Forces have arrived at the remains of the %Value1% system. This once-proud home of the Bulrathi now lies in ruin, with a Guardian of the New Orions standing watch and destroying those who would dare to come here.
\*srMrrGrd Task Forces report the discovery of the shattered %Value1% system, rumored to have been the home system of the Mrrshan civilization. A Guardian of the New Orions now prowls within its bounds, striking swiftly at intruders.
\*srEleGrd You have stumbled upon the ruined system of %Value1%, which legends say was the seat of the vast empire of the Elerians. Now a hollow, smoldering shell of its former glory, a lethal Guardian of the New Orions moves between the worlds of the system, searching for trespassers.
\*srAlkGrd The scattered, broken hulls drifting through %Value1% reveal that you have discovered the lost home system of the proud Alkari fleet. Now, the only active ship in the system is a Guardian of the New Orions, a reminder of what happens to those who dare to oppose their power.
\*ECNSCRP1 Due to maintenance not being paid some Economic buildings on %Value1% have been dismantled.
\*ECNSCRP2 Some Economic buildings on %Value1% have been torn down due to their maintenance not being paid.
\*ECNSCRP3 With no maintenance being paid for their upkeep, some Economic buildings on %Value1% have been dismantled.
\*SOCSCRP1 Due to maintenance not being paid some Social Development buildings on %Value1% have been dismantled.
\*SOCSCRP2 Some Social Development buildings on %Value1% have been torn down due to their maintenance not being paid.
\*SOCSCRP3 With no maintenance being paid for their upkeep, some Social Development buildings on %Value1%.
\*SECSCRP1 Due to maintenance not being paid some Security buildings on %Value1% have been dismantled.
\*SECSCRP2 Some Security buildings on %Value1% have been torn down due to their maintenance not being paid.
\*WARLAP01 Our war with the %Value1% Empire has ended.
\*WARLAP02 The %Value1% Empire has ended their war with us.
\*SECSCRP3 With no maintenance being paid for their upkeep, some Security buildings on %Value1%.
\*SPLINCOL A colony of the %Value1% race has been discovered on %Value2%
\*COLSHP01 Your Colony Ship was unable to reach its destination due to enemy activity.
\*COLPROB1 Our colonization task force failed to land on %Value1%. That planet is already controlled by %Value2%.
\*COLPROB2 Our colonization task force failed to land on %Value1%. The colonists were unable to find an open region to land in.
\*COLPROB3 Our outpost task force failed to land on %Value1%. The planet is already controlled by %Value2%.
\*COLPROB4 Our outpost task force failed to land on %Value1%. The colonists were unable to find an open region to land in.
\*COLPROB5 Our outpost task force failed to land on %Value1%. An outpost belonging to %Value2% has already been established on that planet.
\*COLPROB6 Our outpost task force failed to land on %Value1%. An independent outpost has already been established on that planet.
\*STEAL01 One of our spies has stolen the %Value1% technology from the %Value2% Empire.
\*STEAL02 One of our spies has acquired the %Value1% technology from the %Value2% Empire.
\*STEAL03 One of our spies has robbed the %Value2% Empire. We now possess the %Value1% technology.
\*GFDISBAN Ground Force %Value2% has been disbanded and is returning to your reserves. Its %Value3% unit(s) will be held in the delay box for up to %Value1% turns.
\*TFDISBAN Task Force %Value2% has been disbanded and is returning to your reserves. Its %Value3% ship(s) will be held in the delay box for up to %Value1% turns.
\*ELECT01 The %Value1% Empire has been elected as president of the Orion Senate.
\*ELECT02 After the newest election, the %Value1% Empire still holds its position as president of the Orion Senate.
\*StlTch01 Our counter espionage agents inform us that the technology %Value1% has been stolen from us by agents unknown.
\*StlTch02 Spies have stolen the %Value1% technologies from us!
\*StlTch03 Spies have accessed our Research facilities networks and stolen the %Value1% technology.
\*FCONTAC1 Our diplomats have established contact with the %Value1% Empire.
\*FCONTAC2 Sir, we've encountered a new race. We now have diplomatic channels with the %Value1% Empire.
\*LCONTAC1 Our diplomats have lost contact with the %Value1% Empire.
\*LCONTAC2 Sir, we've lost contact with the %Value1% Empire.
\*RCONTAC1 Our diplomats have re-established contact with the %Value1% Empire.
\*RCONTAC2 Sir, We've re-established contact with the %Value1% Empire.
\*RSVSCRP1 Sir, Some of our ships have been scrapped due to their maintenance not being paid.
\*GCTCHCAP Your ground forces have captured a technology: %Value1%!

\*BILLFAIL The proposed %Value1% bill has failed in the senate.
\*BILL2NDD The proposed %Value1% bill has been seconded and is awaiting your vote. 
\*SNTEJOIN The Orion Senate has approved the membership of the %Value1% empire into its ranks. 
\*SNTEKICK The Orion Senate has voted to revoke the membership of the %Value1% empire. 
\*NEWOUT01 An outpost on %Value1% has been created. 
\*NEWOUT02 An outpost on %Value1% has been established.
\*NEWOUT03 A new outpost on %Value1% has been created.
\*SCTHBMB1 Sir! The %Value1% empire has bombarded the planet %Value2%!
\*SCWEBMB1 Sir! Our space forces have bombarded the planet %Value2% located in the %Value1% empire.
\*SCTHDES1 Sir! The %Value1% empire has DESTROYED the planet %Value2%!
\*SCWEDES1 Sir! Our space forces have DESTROYED the planet %Value2% located in the %Value1% empire. 
\*SCTHPDF1 Sir! Our space forces attacked the defenseless planet %Value1% with ease!
\*SCMYPDF1 Sir! Enemy space forces attacked the planet %Value1% and we had nothing to defend it with!
\*STARLN01 Astronomers have located a previously undiscovered Starlane connecting the %Value1% and %Value2% systems.
\*AntaranRevolt The citizens of the %Value1% empire have revolted and formed the new %Value2% empire!
\*DiscoverSystem Your scientists have intercepted a transmission containing a detailed starmap of the %value1% system.
