\\System Specials
\*spSolWn Strong Stellar Winds
\*spSolWnD Strong Stellar Winds produce a large amount of radiation and elecromagnetic "pollution" in this system.  Items built here are commensurately more expensive.
\*spBtlSt Ancient Battle Site
\*spBtlStD This is an ancient battle field. Ancient and decrepit husks of blasted ships are in orbit around the sun.
\*spBtlLs Battle Lust
\*spBtlLsD An odd chemical reaction produces feelings of euphoria here, especially in stress filled situations such as combat. Units are less likely to retreat from battle in this system.
\*spAntarX Antaran X
\*spAntrXD An Antaran X may be recovered here. 
\\Ancient Battle Sites
\*spBat01 S1
\*spBat01D S1
\*spBat02 S2
\*spBat02D S2
\*spBat03 S3
\*spBat03D S3
\*spBat04 S4
\*spBat04D S4
\*spBat05 S5
\*spBat05D S5
\*spBat06 S6
\*spBat06D S6
\*spBat07 S7
\*spBat07D S7
\*spBat08 S8
\*spBat08D S8
\*spBat09 S9
\*spBat09D S9
\*spBat10 S10
\*spBat10D S10

\\Horror Table
\*spHor01 S11
\*spHor01D S11
\*spHor02 S12
\*spHor02D S12
\*spHor03 S13
\*spHor03D S13
\*spHor04 S14
\*spHor04D S14
\*spHor05 S15
\*spHor05D S15
\*spHor06 S16
\*spHor06D S16
\*spHor07 S17
\*spHor07D S17
\*spHor08 S18
\*spHor08D S18
\*spHor09 S19
\*spHor09D S19
\*spHor10 S20
\*spHor10D S20

\\Monster Type Table

\\Guardian Force Table

\\Regional Specials
\*spAbCol Abandoned Colony
\*spAbColD At one time, this was the site of a colony that belonged to your race.  It is still habitable, though there is no sign of what happened to the previous colonists./p/p

Decreases Building Costs by 10-15%/p
Chance of Finding a Small Colony is 50/p
Chance of Finding a Medium Colony is 35/p
Chance of Finding a Large Colony is 15/p
Increases AUs in the Treasury by 200 to 500 for Medium Colony/p
Increases AUs in the Treasury by 400 to 1000 for Large Colony

\*spVolc Active Volcanoes
\*spVolcD An unusual amount of volcanic activity exists on this planet. This increases the cost of terraforming the planet considerably./p/p

Increases Planetary Terraforming Cost by 50%/p
Decreases Maximum Amount Planet can be Terraformed by 25%

\*spCache Cache
\*spCacheD A cache; see cache table.
\*spCave Cavernous
\*spCaveD This planet has a series of large, inhabitable caves underground.  This allows for more colonists to live on the planet, as well as providing some additional defense in combat./p/p

Increases Maximum Regional Population by 1 /p
Increases Ground Combat Fortification Value by 2

\*spContr Smugglers' Haven
\*spContrD This planet has long been used as a base for smugglers and other outlaws.  Efforts at tax collection and law enforcement will meet with considerable resistance, and valuable materials tend to 'vanish' on a regular basis./p/p

Decreases Government DEA Efficiency by 20%/p
Decreases Military DEA Efficiency by 20%/p
Decreases Rare Bioharvest Value by 20%/p
Decreases Rare Mineral Value by 20%/p
Decreases Craftmanship Value by 20%

\*spOracl Oracle
\*spOraclD 
\*spHorr Horror
\*spHorrD
\*spElcAc Electrical Activity
\*spElcAcD The high amount of electrical activity on this planet interferes with electronics and communications.  As a result, DEAs relying on sensitive electronics and mass-communication are less efficient here./p/p

Decreases Research DEA Capacity by 1 /p
Decreases Manufacturing DEA Efficinecy by 20%/p
Decreases Military DEA Efficiency by 10%/p
Decreases Spaceport DEA Efficiency by 1

\*spMicrb Hostile Microbes
\*spMicrbD This region is infested with hostile microbes.  These microbes are immune to all known anti-bacterial agents, and severely limit population growth.  Nearly all areas of the economy are hampered to some degree, although study of the organisms can benefit research in the areas of medical science and bio-warfare./p/p

Decreases Population Industry by 2/p
Decreases Population Growth Rate by 50%/p
Increases Population Pollution by 4/p
Increases Research DEA Efficiency by 125%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 95%


\*spInsct Hostile Insect Life
\*spInsctD This region is infested with hostile insects.  These insects interfere with most types of production.  Safety precautions and filters make all regional buildings more expensive to build and maintain./p/p

Increases Construction and Maintenance Costs by 50%/p
Decreases Manufacturing Efficiency by 50%/p
Decreases Mine DEA Efficiency by 75%/p
Decreases Bioharvest DEA Efficiency by 75%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 90%

\*spAniml Hostile Animal Life
\*spAnimlD Small hostile animals infest this region.  These animals are mostly pests, getting into food stores and warehouses, but they can also be dangerous in some circumstances, lowering population growth by a small amount./p/p

Decreases Population Growth Rate by 25%/p
Decreases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 2/p
Decreases Bioharvest DEA Efficiency by 40%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 90%

\*spLAnim Large Hostile Animals
\*spLAnimD This region is the preferred hunting ground for packs of large predatory animals.  These animals will snatch livestock and even citizens, reducing both bioharvesting and population growth somewhat.  Some foolish tourists may actually come to this region specifically to hunt these animals./p/p

Increases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 2/p
Decreases Population Growth Rate by 20%/p
Decreases Bioharvest DEA Efficiency 25%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 75%

\*spHAnim Huge Hostile Animals
\*spHAnimD Massive predators roam this region at will.  These dangerous creatures can cause quite a bit of trouble for populations and livestock, but they provide a great training opportunity for shock troops, and in some cases can even be trained for military purposes themselves./p/p

Increases Military DEA Efficiency by 30%/p
Decreases Population Growth Rate by 35%/p
Decreases Bioharvest DEA Efficiency by 30%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 60%

\*spFlora Hostile Flora
\*spFloraD A region of this planet is covered with hostile plant life.  These plants grow wildly and are deleterious to all known life forms.  They will choke and kill most regular food crops, and make for a generally unpleasant atmosphere, even reducing population growth by a small amount./p/p

Decreases Bioharvest DEA Efficiency by 50%/p
Decreases Ecosystem Quality by 1/p
Decreases Population Growth Rate by 15%/p
Decreases Infrastructure by 15%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 80%

\*spHosMn Radioactive Minerals
\*spHosMnD The minerals in this region are contaminated by dangerous radioactive isotopes.  The additional processing and safeguards necessary to work with these minerals will greatly reduce the effectiveness of mining and industry in the region, and the background radiation inhibits population growth./p/p

Decreases Population Growth Rate by 20%/p
Decreases Mining Capacity by 1/p
Decreases Manufacturing Efficiency by 25%/p
Decreases Rare Mineral Value by 50%

\*spWells Natural Wells
\*spWellsD Natural springs of exceptionally pure water exist in abundance in this region, encouraging population growth and tourism.  In addition, the efficiency of industry is boosted slightly by the ready availability of fresh water./p/p

Increases Population Growth Rate by 20%/p
Increases Manufacturing Efficiency by 1/p
Increases Bioharvest Efficiency by 50%/p
Increases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 1/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 90%

\*spThriv Thriving Ecosystem
\*spThrivD The abundance of flora and fauna on this planet has resulted in a veritable cornucopia effect.  Bioharvesting planet-wide is vastly improved./p/p

Increases Bioharvest Efficiency by 50%/p
Increases Ecosystem Quality by 1/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 90%
\*spPoll Fragile Ecosystem
\*spPollD The ecological balance on this planet is precarious at best.  The effects of pollution will be felt much more strongly here than is usually the case, and bioharvesting must be kept reasonably contained.  Also, great care must be taken when terraforming the planet, lest the balance be upset too much./p/p

Increases Pollution by 50%/p
Increases Terraform Costs by 50%/p
Decreases Bioharvest Efficiency by 25%
  
\*spRAnim Menagerie
\*spRAnimD A wide array of rare and unusual animals can be found in this region, increasing the income from bioharvesting and trade, as well as being popular with tourists and biological researchers./p/p

Increases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 2/p
Increases Spaceport Capacity by 1/p
Increases Research Efficiency by 25%/p
Increases Rare Bioharvest Value by 50%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 60%

\*spRFuel Natural Fuels
\*spRFuelD Rare natural fuel types can be found in this region, which provide modest increases to manufacturing and trade while producing considerably less pollution than synthetic fuels./p/p

Increases Manufacturing Efficiency by 3/p
Increases Spaceport Efficiency by 2/p
Decreases Pollution by 50%/p
Decreases Population Pollution by 50%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 90%

\*spRGems Rare Gems
\*spRGemsD Several rare and very pure crystals and gemstones can be found in this region, greatly increasing the value of mineral products and manufactured goods, as well as boosting trade revenue and research./p/p

Increases Research Efficiency by 30%/p
Increases Spaceport Efficiency by 2/p
Increases Craftmanship Value by 50%/p
Doubles Rare Mineral Value

\*spRMetl Rare Metals
\*spRMetlD Several sources of extremely rare metals can be found in this region, which increase the quality and value of mining products and manufactured goods.  The metals can also be traded and used in research./p/p

Increases Manufacturing Efficiency by 50%/p
Increases Mining Efficiency by 25%/p
Increases Craftmanship Value by 30%/p
Increases Rare Mineral Value by 50%

\*spRPtro Rare Petrochemicals
\*spRPtroD Rare chemical fuel types can be found in this region, which increase the effectiveness of manufacturing, research and trade efforts, but reliance on these fuels carries a penalty in increased pollution./p/p

Increases Manufacturing Efficiency by 50%/p
Increases Spaceport Efficiency by 1/p
Increases Research Efficiency by 50%/p
Doubles Pollution

\*spRPlnt Rare Plants
\*spRPlntD This region contains a wide variety of unusual plants.  They may be valued for their nutritious, aesthetic or scientific properties, or they may simply be valuable to others who will pay well for them in trade./p/p

Increases Bioharvest Capacity by 1/p
Increases Population Bioharvesting by 1/p
Increases Spaceport Efficiency by 4/p
Increases Research Efficiency by 25%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 70%

\*spRRdio Rare Radioactives
\*spRRdioD Rare radioactive materials can be found in this region, which are useful for research and manufacturing, and of course can be traded away for quick profits.  The down-side is that background radiation has a deleterious effect on population growth./p/p
 
Decreases Population Growth Rate by 30%/p
Increases Spaceport Efficiency by 4/p
Increases Research Efficiency by 35%/p
Increases Manufacturing Efficiency by 35%

\*spFLUs Primitive Species
\*spFLUsD A barely sentient species inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p

Generates Forced Labor Units/p
Doubles Unrest

\*spStElm Strategic Elements
\*spStElmD 
\*spEvent Event
\*spEventD
\*spWonder Natural Wonders
\*spWondD A series of awe-inspiring natural formations exist in this region.  People will flock to this region from all corners of the empire to view these wonders, and centers of government located here will also benefit from the added prestige./p/p

Increases Government DEA Efficiency by 4/p
Doubles Recreation DEA Efficiency/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 85%

\*spRandRs Random Research
\*spRanRsD A cache of stored research data has been found here. Twenty-five research points will be added at this planet for a short duration.
\*spRnTech Derelict Ship
\*spRnTecD The remains of a crashed vessel are uncovered on this planet.  Some of the technology on-board is apparently recoverable./p/p
\*spResLdr Rescued Leader
\*spResLdD A famous leader has been marooned on this planet for years, and is willing join your civilization in return for being rescued./p/p
\\Cache Table
\*spCach1 Antaran Technology Cache
\*spCach1D An Antaran Technology Cache is located here. The first civ to discover this location gains a random Antaran Technology.
\*spCach2 Horror
\*spCach2D A randomly generated horror is on this planet.
\*spCach3 Repairable Structures
\*spCach3D A series of repairable structures are located here, reducing the cost of building by 25%.
\*spCach4 Pirate Treasure
\*spCach4D A cache of gold, jewels and other valuables have been found here. These have been converted to AUs and the funds added to your treasury.  Once word gets out, treasure hunters from across your empire will flock to this planet, hoping to pick up anything your survey teams might have missed./p/p

Provides 50-500 AUs upon discovery/p
Increases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 1/p
Increases Spaceport Efficiency by 1
\*spCach5 Rare Aphrodisiac
\*spCach5D A rare Aphrodisiac exists here and will increase the planets population growth rate for a short time.
\*spCach6 Data Cache
\*spCach6D A cache of stored research data has been found here.  As much as can be recovered is sent out as soon as possible to all research installations, where it may help with some current projects.
\*spCach7 Antaran Technology Cache 
\*spCach7D An Antaran Technology Cache is located here. The first civ to discover this location gains a random Antaran Technology.

\\Mystic Table
\*spMyst2 S21
\*spMyst2D S21
\*spMyst3 S22
\*spMyst3D S22
\*spMyst4 S23
\*spMyst4D S23
\*spMyst5 S24
\*spMyst5D S24
\*spMyst6 S25
\*spMyst6D S25
\*spMyst7 S26
\*spMyst7D S26
\*spMyst8 S27
\*spMyst8D S27

\\Refugee Table
\*spRefu2 S28
\*spRefu2D S28
\*spRefu3 S29
\*spRefu3D S29
\*spRefu4 S30
\*spRefu4D S30
\*spRefu5 S31
\*spRefu5D S31
\*spRefu6 S32
\*spRefu6D S32
\*spRefu7 S33
\*spRefu7D S33
\*spRefu8 S34
\*spRefu8D S34

\\Ruins Table
\*spRuin2 Archaeological Ruins
\*spRuin2D This planet holds the ruins of several cities, which appear to have been destroyed fairly recently.  They would seem to have been constructed by the Gnolam race.  Small caches of valuables are scattered around the ruins./p/p

  Adds 25-250 AU to Treasury/p
  Increases Research Efficiency by 2/p
  Increases Infrastructure by 15%/p
  Decreases Construction Cost by 20%

\*spRuin3 Archaeological Ruins
\*spRuin3D This planet holds the ruins of several cities, which appear to have been destroyed fairly recently.  They would seem to have been constructed by the Elerian race.  The graceful architecture of these buildings will draw many sight-seers, and it's a shame to tear them down./p/p

  Increases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 2/p
  Increases Research Efficiency by 2/p
  Increases Infrastructure by 15%/p
  Decreases Construction Cost by 15%

\*spRuin4 Archaeological Ruins
\*spRuin4D This planet holds the ruins of several cities, which appear to have been destroyed fairly recently.  They would seem to have been constructed by the Mrrshan race.  Some of their military installations remain more-or-less intact./p/p

  Increases Military DEA Efficiency by 25%/p
  Increases Research Efficiency by 2/p
  Increases Infrastructure by 15%/p
  Decreases Construction Cost by 20%

\*spRuin5 Archaeological Ruins
\*spRuin5D This planet holds the ruins of several cities, which appear to have been destroyed fairly recently.  They would seem to have been constructed by the Bulrathi race.  The defenses here are so well-built that some use may still be made of them./p/p

  Increases Ground Combat Fortification by 3/p
  Increases Research Efficiency by 2/p
  Increases Infrastructure by 10%/p
  Decreases Construction Cost by 25%

\*spRuin6 Archaeological Ruins

\*spRuin6D This planet holds the ruins of several cities, which appear to have been destroyed fairly recently.  They would seem to have been constructed by the Darlok race.  Their remaining technology is protected by unbelievably sophisticated safeguards.  We could learn something from their techniques./p/p

  Increases Research Efficiency by 2/p
  Increases Infrastructure by 20%/p
  Decreases Construction Cost by 15%

\\Slave Races Table
\*spHumn Human Labor
\*spHumnD A lost colony of Humans inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spEvon Evon Labor
\*spEvonD A lost colony of Evons inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spPsi Psilon Labor
\*spPsiD A lost colony of Psilons inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spMek Meklar Labor
\*spMekD A lost colony of Meklar inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spCyn Cynoid Labor
\*spCynD A lost colony of Cynoids inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spSak Sakkra Labor
\*spSakD A lost colony of Sakkra inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spRaas Raas Labor
\*spRaasD A lost colony of Raas inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spGren Grendarl Labor
\*spGrenD A lost colony of Grendarl inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spTri Trilarian Labor
\*spTriD A lost colony of Trilarians inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spNommo Nommo Labor
\*spNommoD A lost colony of Nommo inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spIms Imsaeis Labor
\*spImsD A lost colony of Imsaes inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spEolad Eoladi Labor
\*spEoladD A lost colony of Eoladi inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spSilic Silicoid Labor
\*spSilicD A lost colony of Silicoids inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spKlack Klackon Labor
\*spKlackD A lost colony of Klackons inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spTachi  Tachidi Labor
\*spTachiD A lost colony of Tachidi inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spIthk Ithkul Labor
\*spIthkD A lost colony of Ithkul inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spMeta Darlok Labor
\*spMetaD A lost colony of Darlocks inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spNonCo Noncorporeal Labor
\*spNonCoD A lost colony of Noncorporeals inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spProto Protoplasmic Labor
\*spProtoD A lost colony of Protoplasmics inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spPlant Plant Labor
\*spPlantD A lost colony of Plants inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spFungl Phaigour Labor
\*spFunglD A lost colony of Phaigor inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spAvian Alkari Labor
\*spAvianD A lost colony of Alkari inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spGarga Rhea Labor
\*spGargaD A lost colony of Rhea inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spBulra Bulrathi Labor
\*spBulraD A lost colony of Bulrathi inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spMrrsh Mrrshan Labor
\*spMrrshD A lost colony of Mrrshan inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spEler Elerian Labor
\*spElerD A lost colony of Elerrians inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spGnol Gnolam Labor
\*spGnolD A lost colony of Gnolams inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spElder Elder Labor
\*spElderD A lost colony of Antarans inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units
\*spComBt Combot Labor
\*spComBtD A lost colony of ComBots inhabits this planet. Their primitive technology makes them ideal for enslavement./p/p
Generates Forced Labor Units

\\Planetary Specials
\*spBtlDm Ancient Battle Damage
\*spBtlDmD This planet was heavily damaged during some ancient battle. Battle damage is cheaper to repair than standard terraforming, allowing this planet to be terraformed for less than is normal.
\*spArtPl Artificial Planet
\*spArtPlD
\*spTrap Ancient Defense System
\*spTrapD
\*spEcOrb Eccentric Orbit
\*spEcOrbD This planet has an extremely elliptical orbit, resulting in an exceptionally large seasonal disparity.  It will cost considerably more to terraform the planet and bioharvesting is highly problematic./p/p

Increases Terraform Cost by 80%/p
Decreases Bioharvest Efficiency by 50%

\*spEntEc Entrapping Ecosystem
\*spEntEcD Visitors to this planet must take extreme precautions against the environment, not because it is toxic, but due to retro-virii that force the body to become dependant on substances only found on this planet.  This greatly reduces tourism and trade, and makes it very difficult to get soldiers or government officials to serve here./p/p

Decreases Government Efficiency by 25%/p
Decreases Spaceport Efficiency by 3/p
Decreases Military DEA Efficiency by 40%/p
Decreases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 3/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 90%

\*spHbMon Hibernating Monster
\*spHbMonD
\*spErWth Erratic Weather
\*spErWthD The highly erratic weather patterns on this planet make bioharvesting particularly difficult, and interfere with tourism and trade./p/p

Decreases Spaceport Efficiency by 1/p
Decreases Bioharvest Efficiency by 50%/p
Decreases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 1/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 85%

\*spMetSh Meteor Showers
\*spMetShD 
\*spMgFld Strong Geomagnetic Fields
\*spMgFldD This planet has very strong magnetic fields. These fields interfere with the delicate instruments required for research and manufacturing, and also affect atmospheric and orbital craft, restricting military and trade operations./p/p

Increases Gravity Penalty by 1/p
Decreases Manufacturing Efficiency by 15%/p
Decreases Spaceport Efficiency by 3/p
Decreases Research Efficiency by 40%/p
Increases Ground Combat Fortification by 1/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 95%

\*spHStrm Global Storms
\*spHStrmD Huge, powerful storms rage across this planet constantly. Costs for building and maintaining structures here are greatly increased while bioharvesting is greatly reduced.  Military and civilian aircraft are somewhat hampered as well./p/p

Increases Construction Cost by 80%/p
Increases Maintenance Cost by 90%/p
Decreases Bioharvest Efficiency by 40%/p
Decreases Spaceport Efficiency by 2/p
Decreases Military DEA Efficiency by 10%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 90%

\*spHTect Tectonic Instability
\*spHTectD 
\*spStRng Stratosphere Rings
\*spStRngD This planet has large rings around its equator.  The rings are an excellent tourist attraction and offer some research benefits, but they also provide a convenient hiding place for pirates and other less savory visitors./p/p

Increases Recreation Efficiency by 1/p
Increases Research Efficiency by 20%/p
Decreases Military DEA Efficiency by 50%

\*spHGas Hostile Gases
\*spHGasD The atmosphere of this planet has significant amounts of toxins.  This reduces the efficiency of almost all aspects of life here./p/p

Increases Research Capacity by 3/p
Increases Rare Mineral Value by 250%/p
Increases Building Cost by 50%/p
Decreases Growth Rate by 75%

\*spMagnt Magnate Civilization
\*spMagntD This planet contains a previously unknown colony of a race long thought to be purely mythical, or destroyed by the New Orions.
\*spRpRot Corrosive Atmosphere
\*spRpRotD A large amount of corrosive material is in the atmosphere and soil of this planet, increasing the cost to maintain structures, and reducing the effectiveness of bioharvesting. This material is deadly to all forms of life, and corrosive to most materials. However, the chemicals contained in the atmosphere are of unique origin and of incredible value to research. The atmosphere has enchanced the formation of valuable mineral deposits and allowed them to remain untouched./p/p

Increases Maintenance Cost by 150%/p
Decreases Population Growth by 75%/p
Decreases Bioharvest Efficiency by 75%/p
Increases Research DEA Efficiency by 50%/p
Increases Rare Mineral Value by 50%

\*spSntPl Hostile Planet
\*spSntPlD The life forms on this planet all share a collective mind and greatly resent outside life forms.  The planet itself seems to do everything possible to make your people's lives miserable./p/p

Decreases Population Growth Rate by 25%/p
Increases Unrest by 25%/p
Decreases Amount Planet can be Terraformed by 50%/p
Decreases Bioharvesting Efficiency by 50%/p
Decreases Mining Efficiency by 50%/p
Decreases Government Efficiency by 20%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 90%

\*spSplnt Splinter Colony
\*spSplntD A lost colony of your race has been located!  They are pleased to rejoin your empire after countless cycles./p/p

Maximum Population is between 1.5 and 3
\\Alien Devices Table
\*spAln02 S42
\*spAln02D S42
\*spAln03 S43
\*spAln03D S43
\*spAln04 S44
\*spAln04D S44
\*spAln05 S45
\*spAln05D S45
\*spAln06 S46
\*spAln06D S46
\*spAln07 S47
\*spAln07D S47
\*spAln08 S48
\*spAln08D S48


\\Monster Breeding Table
\*spMns02 S49
\*spMns02D S49
\*spMns03 S50
\*spMns03D S50
\*spMns04 S51
\*spMns04D S51
\*spMns05 S52
\*spMns05D S52
\*spMns06 S53
\*spMns06D S53
\*spMns07 S54
\*spMns07D S54
\*spMns08 S55
\*spMns08D S55

\\Event Table
\*spEvt01 S56
\*spEvt01D S56
\*spEvt02 S57
\*spEvt02D S57
\*spEvt03 S58
\*spEvt03D S58
\*spEvt04 S59
\*spEvt04D S59
\*spEvt05 S60
\*spEvt05D S60

\\Guardians
\*spDarHW Darlok Guardian
\*spDarHWD Your explorations have uncovered the devastated system of Nazin,
once home to the people of the Darlok empire. A Guardian of the New Orions
now occupies the system to keep curiosity-seekers at bay.
\*spBulHW Bulrathi Guardian
\*spBulHWD Your Task Forces have arrived at the remains of the
Ursa system. This once-proud home of the Bulrathi now lies in ruin, with
a Guardian of the New Orions standing watch and destroying those who would
dare to come here.
\*spMrrHW Mrrshan Guardian
\*spMrrHWD Task Forces report the discovery of the shattered Fieras system, rumored to have been the home system of the Mrrshan civilization. A Guardian of the New Orions now prowls within its bounds, striking swiftly at intruders.
\*spElrHW Elerian Guardian
\*spElrHWD You have stumbled upon the ruined system of Draconis, which legends
say was the seat of the vast empire of the Elerians. Now a hollow,
smoldering shell of its former glory, a lethal Guardian of the New Orions
moves between the worlds of the system, searching for trespassers.
\*spAlkHW Alkari Guardian
\*spAlkHWD The scattered, broken hulls drifting through Altair reveal that you have discovered the lost home system of the proud Alkari fleet. Now, the only active ship in the system is a Guardian of the New
Orions, a reminder of what happens to those who dare to oppose their power.
\*spPharm Pharmacopoeia
\*spPharmD This region has an unusual abundance of rare medicinal plants and herbs.  As a result, the population tends to be healthier and more productive here, as well as simply living longer.  The herbs are also a boon to trade and research efforts./p/p 

Increases Population Growth Rate by 25%/p
Increases Research Efficiency by 3/p
Increases Spaceport Efficiency by 3/p
Increases Rare Bioharvest Value by 40%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 50%

\*Starve Starve
\*Piracy Piracy
\*Subjugat Subjugated
\*LongWar War Fatigue
\*PopNoMv Overcrowded
\*UnderSge Under Siege
\*OthRevlt Other Planet in Revolt
\*UnresNBC War Atrocity
\*HiUnempl High Unemployment
\*TechAdvU Technological Advance
\*MilPres Military Presence
\*UnExcess Imperial Military Spending High
\*GovChange Government Change
\*UnDeficit Imperial Military Spending Low

\\New Specials
\*spSInst Seismic Instability
\*spSInstD A region of this planet sits upon a major tectonic fault line.  Earthquakes and other seismic disturbances are common, and all buildings have to be specially constructed, not to mention frequently repaired or rebuilt, increasing their cost dramatically.  Also, mining in some areas is totally out of the question, and fears of a major disaster adversely affect trade and recreation./p/p

Increases Construction and Maintenance Costs by 50%/p
Decreases Mine Efficiency by 50%/p
Decreases Spaceport Efficiency by 2/p
Decreases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 2

\*spFPln Friendly Planet
\*spFPlnD This planet has achieved a sort of mass sentience, which has learned to communicate with others.  The planet is curious and eager to learn about other intelligent life forms.  It is willing to help create the perfect environment for members of your race to live here, but requires that heavy industry be kept to a minimum./p/p

Can be Terraformed up to Paradise/p
Decreases Terraform Cost by 60%/p
Increases Bioharvest Efficiency by 25%/p
Increases Population Growth by 25%/p
Increases Recreation DEA Efficiency by 2/p
Decreases Manufacturing Efficiency by 50%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 85%

\*spSoRa Intense Solar Radiation
\*spSoRaD The atmosphere of this planet blocks much less of the sun's radiation than is normal, significantly reducing both bioharvesting and population growth, and playing havoc with planetary sensors, while providing a small boost to industry from the cheap and plentiful solar power./p/p

Decreases Galaxy Sensor Range by 50%/p
Decreases Manufacturing Efficiency by 25%/p
Decreases Population Growth Rate by 20%/p
Decreases Bioharvest Efficiency by 25%/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 85%

\*spOrDe Orbital Debris
\*spOrDeD A large quantity of debris clutters up the orbit of this planet, making it difficult for ships to land or take off, and significantly reducing your ability to do any serious construction in orbit.  The only good news is that some of the debris is quite rich in valuable minerals, which should help your mining efforts./p/p

Decreases Shipyard Capacity by 1/p
Increases Mining Efficiency by 35%/p
Decreases Spaceport Efficiency by 2

\*spLPst Ancient Listening Post
\*spLPstD This planet contains ancient monitoring devices left by some long-forgotten race.  The technology is too alien to be reverse-engineered by your scientists, but the equipment itself appears to still be in decent working order./p/p

Increases Galaxy Sensor Range by 500
\*spPsych Rare Psychotropics
\*spPsychD Growing wild on this planet are plants and herbs with potent mind-altering effects. Use of these drugs reduces unrest sharply on the planet, and increases trade profits, but at the cost of rendering the local populace much less productive than normal./p/p

Decreases Unrest by 50%/p
Increases Spaceport Efficiency by 3/p
Decreases Population Industry by 1/p
Decreases Population Research by 1/p/p

Chance to Survive Terraforming: 75%
  
