\*TRAINSD1 Military Espionage Report: One of our undercover agents has caused havoc with the %Value1%'s reserves. Several of their ships have been put into dry dock for repairs and will be out of commission for a few cycles.
\*TRAINSD2 Military Espionage Report: %Value1% training camps have been penetrated by our agents. Several of their ships have been damaged and are in need of repair.
\*TRAINRC1 Our ship reserves have been disrupted by enemy agents. Several ships are unavailable while repairs are made.
\*TRAINRC2 Rogue elements have infiltrated our ship reserves and disabled several vessels. They are undergoing repairs.
\*SUPRTSD1 Military Espionage Report: Our spies have disrupted the %Value1%'s military reserves. Several of their best ground units have been temporarily disbanded.
\*SUPRTSD2 Military Espionage Report: The %Value1% support forces have been thrown into chaos by our spies. Their ground forces will need time to reorganize several of their units before they can mount an attack.
\*SUPRTRC1 Enemy spies have struck our reserve forces! Many of our troops have been sent to the infirmary. 
\*SUPRTRC2 Our armies' databases have been tampered with by enemy agents. It will take some time to undo the damage. 
\*REPARSD1 Military Espionage Report: Ships in the %Value1% repair facilities have been struck by our saboteurs. Their repair facilities have been damaged and it will take longer for them to accomplish repairs.
\*REPARSD2 Military Espionage Report: Our agents have successfully damaged ships in the %Value1% Empire's repair yards.
\*REPARRC1 Foreign agents infiltrated our repair yards. Several ships have suffered damage and will require additional time to be repaired.
\*REPARRC2 Spies have gotten to our repair yards and damaged several facilities. We're starting on the repairs immediately.
\*MILTBSD1 Social Espionage Report: Our covert operations department reports the demolition of a %Value1% military facility.
\*MILTBSD2 Social Espionage Report: A %Value1% military building was destroyed by one of our saboteurs.
\*MILTBRC1 Terrorists have destroyed our %Value2% on %Value1%!
\*MILTBRC2 Our %Value2% on %Value1% has been destroyed by unknown forces. Someone must pay.
\*MILTPSD1 Spy Report: We have tampered with the production queues on a %Value1% planet. Won't they be surprised.
\*MILTPSD2 Spy Report: A %Value1% planet's military production line has been altered by our deep cover personnel.
\*MILTPRC1 Our production lines on %Value1% have been hacked by a hostile intelligence agency. Production has decreased on that planet slightly.
\*MILTPRC2 %Value1% reports that some of its military production queues have been sabotaged. Our production there has been decreased.
\*MOBLESD1 Military Espionage Report: Our spies have struck a mighty blow against the %Value1% reserve fleet. Several of their ships have been completely destroyed.
\*MOBLESD2 Military Espionage Report: A great victory for our covert operations teams, who left the %Value1% reserve fleet in flames.
\*MOBLERC1 The reserve fleet we have worked so hard to build has been irreparably damaged by saboteurs. Ships that have been sent in for repair: %Value1%.
\*MOBLERC2 Our reserves are in flames! Ships that have been sent in for repair: %Value1%.
\*GOVSBSD1 Diplomatic Espionage Report: Clandestine operatives have targeted a %Value1% government building for destruction in 3.  2.  1.   BOOM!
\*GOVSBSD2 Diplomatic Espionage Report: One of our covert ops teams has destroyed a Government building in the %Value1% Empire.
\*GOVSBRC1 A %Value2% building on %Value1% was destroyed. A cloaked figure was spotted leaving the scene!
\*GOVSBRC2 A suspicious "accident" has destroyed a %Value2% on %Value1%. Enemy spies are suspected.
\*GOVEBSD1 Social Espionage Report: The %Value1% are a little weaker today, as our saboteurs have destroyed one of their vital factories.
\*GOVEBSD2 Social Espionage Report: Our spies have proven their worthiness yet again by wiping several factories off the face of their planet.
\*GOVEBRC1 The obliteration of a %Value2% on %Value1% by villainous saboteurs will have a grave impact on our economy.
\*GOVEBRC2 One of our %Value2% buildings on planet %Value1% has been destroyed by saboteurs.
\*CIVTDSD1 Economic Espionage Report: Our intelligence agency has wisely targeted the %Value1% freighter network and thrown it into complete disarray.
\*CIVTDSD2 Economic Espionage Report: %Value1% freighters are running a little less smoothly, thanks to our skilled field agents.
\*CIVTDRC1 Enemy spies have hit a new low, striking at our unarmed freighters. Our trade income has been affected.
\*CIVTDRC2 Hostile agents have tampered with our freighters. As a result, our trade income has suffered.
\*RECCBSD1 Social Espionage Report: A recreation building in the %Value1% Empire has been destroyed by our agents.
\*RECCBSD2 Social Espionage Report: Our covert demolitions unit in the %Value1% Empire has struck one of their recreation facilities, leveling it to the ground.
\*RECCBRC1 A %Value2% building on %Value1% was destroyed. 
\*RECCBRC2 A %Value2% building on %Value1% was destroyed. 
\*CIVFRSD1 Spy Report: Our agents are using brute force to strike fear in the hearts of the %Value1% people and causing unrest.
\*CIVFRSD2 Spy Report: The %Value1% people are afraid of us, and with good reason. Our spies walk among them causing unrest.
\*CIVFRRC1 Our people cower in fear of enemy terror tactics. Empire wide unrest is increasing.
\*CIVFRRC2 Someone is terrorizing our citizens and causing unrest. This has to stop now.
\*SCIBDSD1 Scientific Espionage Report: Scientific progress has come to a sudden, explosive end in the %Value1% Empire.
\*SCIBDSD2 Scientific Espionage Report: Our saboteurs' plan to collapse a science facility in the %Value1% Empire has succeeded admirably.
\*SCIBDRC1 A bomb went off in our %Value2% on %Value1%, destroying it utterly.
\*SCIBDRC2 One of our enemies has destroyed a %Value2% on %Value1%. 
\*PROFDSD1 Scientific Espionage Report: Our field agents have slowed %Value1% research to a crawl.
\*PROFDSD2 Scientific Espionage Report: The march of %Value1% science has just taken an about-face, with a little help from our spies.
\*PROFDRC1 One of our research projects has been sabotaged! We will lose a lot of time undoing the damage.
\*PROFDRC2 Our cowardly foes have lashed out at our research facilities, slowing down one of our projects.
\*UNIPFSD1 Scientific Espionage Report: Our agents have distracted %Value1% researchers from their current work.
\*UNIPFSD2 Scientific Espionage Report: Our black ops squad in the %Value1% Empire has convinced certain researchers not to return to work. Ever.
\*UNIPFRC1 Assassins have taken out several of our researchers!
\*UNIPFRC2 One of our rivals is using hit men to strike at our scientists. 
\*MJGOVSD1 Scientific Espionage Report: We have struck a great blow against the %Value1% scientific community! They will require many cycles to repair the laboratories we have destroyed!
\*MJGOVSD2 Scientific Espionage Report: Our operatives have launched a daring strike against the %Value1%'s scientific facilities. Their research efforts will surely be disrupted.
\*MJGOVRC1 Radical agents have caused wanton destruction of science facilities on %Value1%. Our research projects will be delayed because of this.
\*MJGOVRC2 The scientific community mourns the loss of so many people and facilities in terrorist attacks on %Value1% this cycle. The loss is irreparable.
\*LDKILL01 Political Espionage Report: One of our operatives has poisoned a %Value1% Military leader. He won't survive much longer.
\*LDKILL02 Political Espionage Report: One of our operatives has taken steps to eliminate a %Value1% Planetary leader. He will die shortly.
\*LDKILL03 Political Espionage Report: One of our operatives has poisoned a %Value1% leader. He won't survive much longer.
\*LDKILL04 One of our Military Leaders has been poisoned. He's not expected to last much longer.
\*LDKILL05 Spies have assaulted one of our leaders. %Value1% is not expected to survive the night.
\*SCANDA01 %Value1% is accusing us of sending spies into their Empire. We thought our spy activities had been hidden better than that.
\*SCANDA02 %Value1% is reporting to its citizens that their recent spy attacks were caused by us. We have disputed these untrue remarks.
\*SCANDA03 We've found evidence that our recent spy attacks were sent by %Value1%. We should make them pay!
\*FORREL01 Spy Report: We have greased the right palms and planted the right stories.  The citizens of %Value1% have developed a better opinion of us!
\*FORREL02 We've found evidence of a covert diplomatic mission within our empire. Further investigation is underway.
\*LAYLOW01 Espionage Report: Operatives are laying low and developing sources in the %Value1% Empire.
\*LAYLOW02 Espionage Report: Operatives inserted in the %Value1% empire are making progress.  They will launch their next operation shortly.
\*LAYLOW03 Espionage Report: Our black ops team is evaluating its target in the %Value1% empire. Vigilant internal security at the target location requires further preparation.
\*LAYLOW04 We have detected enemy covert agents inside our empire.  Our counter-intelligence operations have driven them underground.
\*LAYLOW05 We've found evidence of foreign spy operations within our borders.
\*LAYLOW06 Enemy operatives are believed to be operating within our borders.  Internal security is working to eliminate them.
\*HFOGUPS1 Government bureaucracy in the %Value1% empire will be less efficient thanks to our political interference.
\*HFOGUPT1 A corruption in our administrative and finance systems is causing havoc in our economic efficiency.
\*ECONBIO1 Spy Report: We have tampered with the harvesting plans on a %Value1% planet. Food production will be impaired.
\*ECONBIO2 Spy Report: A %Value1% planet's bioharvesting facilities have been impacted by our deep cover personnel.
\*ECONBIT1 Our bioharvesting abilities on %Value1% have been hacked by a hostile intelligence agency. Bioharvesting has decreased on that planet slightly.
\*ECONBIT2 %Value1% reports that some of its bioharvesting production queues have been sabotaged. Our bioharvesting there has been decreased.
\*ECONMIN1 Spy Report: We have tampered with the mining plans on a %Value1% planet. Won't they be surprised.
\*ECONMIN2 Spy Report: A %Value1% planet's mine production line has been altered by our deep cover personnel.
\*ECONMIT1 Our mining facilities on %Value1% have been hacked by a hostile intelligence agency. Mining has decreased on that planet slightly.
\*ECONMIT2 %Value1% reports that some of its mining facilities have been sabotaged. Our mineral production there has been decreased.
\*SCISABO1 Spy Report: We have tampered with the research database on a %Value1% planet. 
\*SCISABO2 Spy Report: A %Value1% planet's research facilities have been manipulated by our deep cover personnel.
\*SCISABT1 Our research facilities on %Value1% have been hacked by a hostile intelligence agency. Research has decreased on that planet slightly.
\*SCISABT2 %Value1% reports that some of its research facilities have been sabotaged. Our research there has been decreased.
\*ARMYDES1 Military Espionage Report: We have influenced several leaders and troopers in %Value1%'s Empire to desert.
\*ARMYDES2 Several of our units are suffering from drastically increased desertions.
\*PLAUNRV1 Spy Report: We have influenced the administrators of a %Value1% planet to attempt to seize independence.  Time will tell how events play out.
\*PLAUNRV2 We are experiencing massive unrest on %Value1%.
\*PLAUNRV3 Espionage Report: Internal security reports that some of our administrators on %Value1% are attempting to rally popular support in order to seize independence.
\*MINEDES1 Political Espionage Report: Operatives have caused a mining revolt in the %Value1% Empire, resulting in it's complete annihlation.
\*MINEDESA A suspicious "accident" has destroyed a %Value2% on %Value1%. Enemy spies are suspected.
\*FARMDES1 Political Espionage Report: Operatives have caused a worker revolt in a bioharvesting facility in the %Value1% Empire, resulting in its destruction.
\*FARMDESA A suspicious "accident" has destroyed a %Value2% on %Value1%. Enemy spies are suspected.
\*LEADBRI1 Diplomatic Espionage Report: Our Operatives performed their mission well. Certain enemy leaders feel much less obligated to perform their duties.
\*LEADBRIA Certain factions headed by our more influential leaders have publicly condemned our recent action. Enemy Operatives may be behind this. 
\*SPDESTR1 Economic Espionage Report: Our Operatives have completely destroyed a Spaceport in the %Value1% Empire.
\*SPDESTR1 Sir! A sizable warhead was detonated inside one of our main Spaceports! We must find the culprits and make them pay!
\*REBELLI1 Political Espionage Report: An Operative has sparked a nuclear war on a planet in the %Value1% empire. Countless building were been destroyed and lives were lost in the horrific battle
\*REBELLIA Terrible News! An enemy Operative has sparked a nuclear war on %Value1%. The casualties are horrific!
\*FACTION1 Political Espionage Report: We have convinced several countries on a %Value1% planet to go declare war on each other. The destruction is widespread and will not cease for several cycles.
\*FACTIONA %Value1% has erupted in a major civil war due to enemy agents. Many building have been razed to the ground.
\*GOVCHAI1 Diplomatic Espionage Report: Our operatives have performed their missions well. A chain of governmental buildings in the %Value1% empire were completely destroyed.
\*GOVCHAIA Enemy operatives seized control of several prominent goverment buildings and burned them to the ground. We must find the culprits and make them pay!
\*MINECHA1 Political Espionage Report: Our operatives report that their mission was all too easy. They managed to destroy several prominent mines of the %Value1%.
\*MINECHAA Unknown operatives headed several rebellions in our mining sector! The riot raged out of control and several mining operations were destroyed before riot police could restore peace.
\*CHAINDE1 Economic Espionage Report: Our operatives manged to destroy a cluster of Space Ports in the %Value1% empire's center of commerce! They may never be able to repair the damage!
\*CHAINDEA A coordinated terrorist has completely destroyed several of our most valuable Space Ports! We must find the empire that funded such an operation!
\*GOVSBSDA Political Espionage Report: Clandestine operatives have targeted a %Value1% government building for destruction in 3.  2.  1.   BOOM!
\*GOVSBSDB Political Espionage Report: One of our covert ops teams has destroyed a Government building in the %Value1% Empire.
\*GOVSBRCA A %Value2% building on %Value1% was destroyed. A cloaked figure was spotted leaving the scene!
\*GOVSBRCB A suspicious "accident" has destroyed a %Value2% on %Value1%. Enemy spies are suspected.


