\\ Description of spy types and missions

\*SPMILRIN Organizes and operates spy rings.

\*SPMILREC Solicits Military personnel

\*SPMILSIG High: Acquires Current Army Reserves Listing, Acquired Current Fleet 
Reserves Listing, Acquires Listing of Recent Movement Orders, Acquires Listing of recently Mobilized/ Demobilized Armies and Task Forces, Acquires Prototype Military Building Design, Acquires Prototype Weapon Design, Acquires Prototype Military Achievement, Acquires Unknown Prototype Ship Design, Preview of all Military Events the target civilization currently holds, View Dossier on Head of the War Department
/p/pMedium: Acquires Current Draft Pool Information, Acquires Current Unit Deployments in a Single Sector, Acquires Current Listing of all Military Construction, Acquires Current Listing of all Units and Draft Pool Points in Delay, Acquires Current Weapons Use Policies, Acquires In Service Military Achievement, Acquires In Service Ship Design, Acquires Weapon Design, View the Dossier on a random Mid Level Military Leader 
/p/pLow: Acquires Current Draft Pool Recruitment Policy, Acquires Current Occupation Policy, Acquires Current Planetary and Jump Point Defenses data, Acquires Current Slaves in the Military Policy, Discovers the Current Number of Military DEAs, Discovers One Current Strategic Element, View the Dossier on a random Task Force Commanders

\*SPMILPRO Army Desertions Prompted, Command Indecision / Conflicting Orders, Corruption of the Military, Draft Riots Incited, Estrange the Military, Navy Desertions Prompted, Training Disrupted

\*SPMILBLI Military Building Destroyed, Military Production Sabotaged, Mobilization Center Hit, Repair Facilities Targeted, Replacement Centers Bombed, Strategic Element Stockpile Hit, Supply Lines Disrupted, Support Unit Buildup Disrupted, Training Depots Terrorized, Transport Reserves Disrupted

\*SPMILSHI Assassinates officers, cracks Military Code, disrupts flow of one Strategic Resource, Steals Active Ship Design (i.e. not retired), Steals Military Building tech, Steals Grunt Personal Weapons tech, Steals Planetary Defense tech, Steals Ship tech.


\*SPPOLRIN Organizes and operates spy rings.

\*SPPOLREC Solicits Political personnel

\*SPPOLSIG High: Acquires Prototype Government / Social Building Design, Acquires Prototype Political Achievement, Discovers Current Rebellion Policy, Discovers Proof of Dealing with Antarans Recently, Obtains a Listing of Incongruous Military Deployments, Preview of all Political Events, Views Dossier on the Big Leader, Views Dossier on random Secret Associate, Views Dossier on Vice-Leader / Heir
/p/pMedium: Acquires an In Service Government / Social Achievement, Acquires an In Service Government / Social Building Design, Discovers Current Disinformation Settings, Discovers Current Factional Alignment, Discovers Current Oppressometer Settings, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Draft Pool Recruitment, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Leader Recruitment, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Slavery: Military, Views the Dossier on random member of Leader's Entourage, Views Red SitRep
/p/pLow: Discovers Current Enfranchisement Settings, Discovers Current Government Agenda, Discovers Current Number of Government / Social DEAs, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Bread, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Church & State, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Circuses, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Current Political / Military Economy, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Draft Pool Recruitment, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Individual Rights, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Justice System, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Monetary Policy: Budgetary Policy, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Press Freedom, Discovers "The Speechs" Given, General Corruption at Court Report, Views Yellow SitRep

\*SPPOLPRO Attempted coup, Corruption of the Leader Faction, Corruption of the Leader's Entourage Faction, Corruption of the Political Elite Faction, Corruption of the Vice-Leader/Heir Faction, Estrange the Leader Faction, Estrange the Leader's Entourage, Estrange the Political Elite, Estrange the Vice-Leader/Heir

\*SPPOLBLI Government / Social Building Destroyed, Terrorist Acts Create Political Extremes, Terrorist Acts Distract Government, Terrorist Acts Distract Government Leadership

\*SPPOLSHI Assassination of Leaders at Court, Scandal, Steals Political Building tech.


\*SPECORIN Organizes and operates spy rings.

\*SPECOREC Solicits Economic personnel

\*SPECOSIG High: Acquires Prototype Bioharvesting Building Design, Acquires Prototype Economic Achievement, Acquires Prototype Economic Building Design, Acquires Prototype Manufacturing Building Design, Acquires Prototype Mining Building Design, Discovers Current Estimated GDP, Discovers Imperial Budget, Discovers from Whom Regular Tribute Payments are received, Discovers to Whom Regular Tribute Payments are Made, Preview of all Economic Events, Views Dossier on Budget & Finance Director
/p/pMedium: Acquires In Service Economic Achievement, Acquires In Service Economic Building Design, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Monetary Policy: Currency Strength, Discovers Economic Trade Agreements, Discovers Who is Being Embargoed by, Discovers Who is Embargoing, Views Dossier Interstellar Commerce Committee Chair
/p/pLow: Discovers Current Imperial Tax Rate, Discovers Current Interest Rates, Discovers Current Number of Bioharvesting DEAs, Discovers Current Number of Manufacturing DEAs, Discovers Current Number of Mining DEAs, Discovers Current Number of Space Ports, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Monetary Policy: Fix or Float?, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Tax Burden, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Tax Code, Update Jump Lane Maps

\*SPECOPRO Corruption of the Economic Elite, Corruption of the Upper Class, Denounce the Economy, Estrange the Economic Elite, Estrange the Upper Class, Support Piracy

\*SPECOBLI Civilian Trade Disrupted, Civilian Transportation Disrupted, Economic Building Destroyed, Jump Lane Sabotaged

\*SPECOSHI Assassination of Economic Leaders, Counterfeiting, Economic Crisis, Steals Economic Building tech. 


\*SPSOCRIN Organizes and operates spy rings.

\*SPSOCREC Solicits Social personnel

\*SPSOCSIG High: Acquires Prototype Recreation / Cultural Achievement, Acquires Prototype Recreation / Cultural Building Design, Discovers Prototype Antaran X: Antaran Outlook, Discovers Prototype Antaran X: Social Structure, Previews all Social Events
/p/pMedium: Acquires Achieved Antaran X: Antaran Outlook, Acquires Achieved Antaran X: Social Structure, Acquires In Service Recreation / Cultural Building Design, Acquires In Service Social Achievement, General Unrest Report, Views Dossier on Societal Relations Director
/p/pLow: Discovers Current Number of Recreation / Cultural DEAs, Discovers Current Oppressometer Setting for Slaves, Discovers Current Oppressometer Setting for The Masses, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Citizen Indenture: Education, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Citizen Indenture: Military, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Citizen Indenture: Militia, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Citizen Indenture: Public, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Citizen Indenture: Social, Discovers Current Policy Setting for General Slavery Policy, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Education, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Punishment, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Race Relations: Different Species, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Race Relations: Same Species, Different Race, Discovers Current Policy Setting for Slavery: Domestic Aliens, Discovers Current Policy Setting for The Arts, General Societal Report, General Census Data

\*SPSOCPRO Corruption of the Media Faction, Corruption of the Middle Class Faction, Corruption of the Moral Intelligentsia Faction, Corruption of the Lower Class Faction, Estrange the Lower Class Faction, Estrange the Media Faction, Estrange the Middle Class Faction, Estrange the Moral Intelligentsia Faction, Ethnic Revolt, Ethnic Unrest, Rabble Rousing, Organic Slave Revolt, Robotic Slave Revolt

\*SPSOCBLI Citizens Fear for Safety, Estrange the Lower Class Faction, Estrange the Middle Class Faction, Estrange the Upper Class Faction, Recreational / Cultural Building Destroyed

\*SPSOCSHI Not Applicable


\*SPDIPRIN Organizes and operates spy rings.

\*SPDIPREC Solicits Diplomatic personnel

\*SPDIPSIG High: Acquires Prototype Diplomatic Achievement, Acquires Prototype Diplomatic Building Design, Discovers Full Military Alliance Partners, Discovers Proof of Recent Dealings with the Antarans, Previews all Diplomatic Events, Views Dossier on Head of the Foreign Office, Views Dossier on Orion Ambassador, Who is Granting Which Strategic Element Access, Who is Receiving Which Strategic Element Access from the target civilization
/p/pMedium: Acquires In Service Diplomatic Achievement, Acquires In Service Diplomatic Building Design, Discovers Anti-Piracy Trade Agreement Partners, Discovers Defensive Military Alliance Partners, Discover Open Border Trade Agreement Partners, Discovers Who is Being Embargoed, Discovers Who is Embargoing, Faction / Union Update, Latest Peace Terms Offered, Updates Relations Bar Values
/p/pLow: Discovers Non-Aggression Pact Partners, List Recognized Borders by, List Recognized Borders from, Update Casus Belli Values, Who is Granting Trade Concessions, Who is Receiving Trade Concessions

\*SPDIPPRO Diplomatic Incident, Foreign Affairs Emergencies Stirred Up, Instigation, Major Diplomatic Incident

\*SPDIPBLI Not Applicable

\*SPDIPSHI Assassinates Diplomatic Leaders, cracks Diplomatic Code, Diplomatic Incident, Major Diplomatic Incident, Steals Diplomatic Building tech.


\*SPSCIRIN Organizes and operates spy rings.

\*SPSCIREC Solicits Scientific personnel

\*SPSCISIG High: Acquires Prototype Scientific Achievement, Acquires Prototype Scientific Building Design, Acquires Unknown Random Project completed, Acquires Unknown Random Project Prototype, Discovers Prototype Antaran X: Genetics, Discovers Prototype Antaran X: Scientific Approach, Previews all Scientific Events, Views Dossier on Science & Research Head 
/p/pMedium: Acquires In Service Scientific Achievement, Acquires In Service Scientific Building Design, Acquires Achieved Antaran X: Genetics, Acquires Achieved Antaran X: Scientific Approach, Acquires Known Random Project completed, Lists Antaran Expeditionary Forces, View the Dossier on random Project Leaders
/p/pLow: Acquires Field Research data, Acquires Unknown Random Project completed, Discovers Current Number of Research DEAs, Updates Knowledge of all Field Research Levels Institutionalized

\*SPSCIPRO Corruption of the Scientific Intelligentsia Faction, Estrange the Scientific Intelligentsia Faction, Orchestrated Sabotage by a Group of Scientists, Passive Sabotage by a Rogue Scientist, Scientific Defections, Scientific "Brain Drain", Scientists Provoked into Speaking Too Freely

\*SPSCIBLI Project Facility Damaged, Major Government Research Facility Damaged, Science Building Destroyed, University Professors Neutralized

\*SPSCISHI Assassinate Key Researchers, Assassinates Science Leaders, Steals Antaran X technologies, Steals Developed Project Data, Steals Project Data, Steals Scientific Building tech. 


\*SPADMRIN Organizes and operates spy rings.

\*SPADMREC Solicits Administrative personnel

\*SPADMSIG High: Acquires Prototype Administrative Achievement, Acquires Prototype Administrative Building Design, Previews all Administrative Events, Views Dossier on Personnel Director
/p/pMedium: Acquires In Service Administrative Achievement, Acquires In Service Administrative Building Design, Discovers Research Point Output, Views Dossier on Bureau of Statistics Director, Views Dossier on Censor
/p/pLow: Discovers Bioharvest Output, Discovers Manufacturing Output, Discovers Mining Output, Discovers Space Port Gross Income, Identify All Sector and System Seats of Government on Known Planets, Updates all Univalues, Updates Jump Lane Maps

\*SPADMPRO Administrative "Glitch" Introduced into the Imperial Administration, Administrative "Glitch" Introduced into the Halls of Power, A Leader's Ambition Flame is Fanned, Computer Virus Infects Bureaucracy, Corruption of the Bureaucracy Faction, Estrange the Bureaucracy, Strikes/ Shutdowns/ Slowdowns Hinder Government, Rogue Viceroy Talked into Vying for Independence, Rogue System Administrator Talked into Vying for Independence

\*SPADMBLI Not Applicable

\*SPADMSHI Assassinates Administrative Leaders, Managerial Crisis.


\*SPINTRIN Organizes and operates spy rings.

\*SPINTREC Solicits Intelligence personnel

\*SPINTSIG High: Acquires Prototype Intelligence Achievement, Acquires Prototype Intelligence Building Design, Passes Along all High Level SIG Information concerning other civilizations acquired this turn, Previews all Intelligence Events, Views Dossier on Chief of Code Breaking, Views Dossier on Codes Czar, Views Dossier on Chief of Signal Intelligence 
/p/pMedium: Acquires In Service Intelligence Achievement, Acquires In Service Intelligence Building Design, Lists all other civilization currently Spying upon / Not Spying upon / or with a Curtail Espionage Activity Agreement, Passes Along all Medium Level SIG Information concerning other civilizations acquired this turn, Views Dossier on Intelligence Director, Views Dossier on Internal Security Director
/p/pLow: Discovers Current Age of Codes, Discovers Current Disinformation Settings, Discovers Current Oppressometer Settings, Passes Along all Low Level SIG Information concerning other civilizations acquired this turn, 

\*SPINTPRO Convince an Active Operative to Retire, Convince a Passive Operative to Retire, Corruption of the Internal Security Faction, Estrange the Internal Security Faction

\*SPINTBLI Not Applicable

\*SPINTSHI Assassinates Intelligence Personnel, Cracks Intelligence Code, Steals Intelligence tech.


\*SPOUTRIN Organizes and operates spy rings.

\*SPOUTREC Solicits Outlaw personnel

\*SPOUTSIG Medium: List all the other civilization currently with a Curtail Piracy Activity Agreement, Previews all Outlaw Events
/p/pLow: List all known Pirate Events, List all Pirate Raid Table Results, Views Dossier on Random Outlaw Leader

\*SPOUTPRO Not Applicable

\*SPOUTBLI Not Applicable

\*SPOUTSHI Assassinate Outlaw Leaders.
