\\Technology Screen
\*TECHTITL TECHNOLOGY

\\Research
\*TCHRSRCH RESEARCH
\*TCHSCHOL SCHOOL
\*TCHUPCOM UPCOMING POSSIBILITIES
\*TCHINFOR Information
\*TCHCURRR CURRENT RESEARCH
\*TCHRITMS RESEARCH ITEMS
\*TCHTURNS TURNS REMAINING
\*TCHOVERV Selected Item Overview
\*TCHRPAVL TOTAL RESEARCH POINTS AVAILABLE: 
\*TCHRPEXP RESEARCH POINTS EXPECTED NEXT TURN: 
\*TCHPRJST /p/pProject status:/p
\*TCHSCLLV L%levelNum%

\\Notable events for a project
\!TCHEV
\-Visible
\-Prototype available
\-Project available
\-Project started
\-Overrun
\-Positive overrun
\-Sabotaged
\-Completed

\\Matrix
\*TCHMATRX MATRIX
\*TCHLEVLF L%levelNum%
\*TCHRSCHG Researching
\*TCHVIWBY VIEW BY: 
\*TCHIINFO SELECTED ITEM INFORMATION: 
\*TCHNAMEF %techName%, LEVEL %levelNum%
\*TCHREQRS %techName%, LEVEL %levelNum% Req.: %addReqs%
\*TCHADDRQ %fieldName% L%level%
\*TCHMSCHF %schoolName%, Current Level: %levelNum%, Next Level: %progress%%% done. 

\\Descriptions of the tech schools taken from the encyclopedia files
\*SchEconD This school studies practices and institutions that involve, or have significant effects on, the production and allocation of resources under conditions of scarcity. Theories include that of Law, Economics, Process Engineering and Education.

\*SchEnerD This school investigates the underlying structure and functioning of the universe by studying the nature of the various forces at work within it. It involves theories in Relativistic Physics, Quantum Mechanics, Subatomic Physics, Energy Fields, Matter-Energy Conversion, Transwarp Physics, Temporal Physics, Optronics, Quantum Electronics and Transdimensional Electronics. Its benefits include new weapon types and shield abilities. 

\*SchBioSD This school investigates the structure and functioning of living organisms and life processes. It involves Bio-Electronics, Bio-Harvesting, Medicine, Genomics, Bio-Engineering, Nano-Medicine and Xeno-Biology. Its primary benefits relate to farming and medicine. 

\*SchMathD This school investigates the structure and functioning of symbolic systems and their practical applications. The theories it involves are those of Computer Science, Number Theory, Game Theory and Robotics. Its benefits involve primarily Robotics and Artificial Intelligence but it tends to overlap a number of related areas as well. 

\*SchPhySD This school investigates the underlying structure and functioning of the universe by studying the nature of matter. Funding this area of research involves theories into Astro-Engineering, Astro-Physics, Construction, Materials Science, Mineral Extraction and Planetology. Its primary benefits include new methods for building materials, mining procedures and construction. 

\*SchSocaD This school investigates the thoughts, behavior, and institutions of sentient life forms with a strong emphasis on understanding their frames of reference and on facilitating cooperative activity. Associated theories include Psychology, Xeno-Psychology, Political Science, Philosophy, Cultural Enhancement, Criminology and Military Science. Primary benefits include tactics, diplomacy and race relations. 

\*SchEconB Economics
\*SchMathm Mathematics
\*SchEnerg Energy
\*SchBioSc Biology Sciences
\*SchPhySc Physical Sciences
\*SchSocal Social Sciences

\*SchEcon2 Economics:
\*SchMath2 Math:
\*SchEner2 Energy:
\*SchBioS2 Biology Sci:
\*SchPhyS2 Physical Sci:
\*SchSoca2 Social Sci:
